<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>ankursinha.in/blog - Life</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ankursinha.in/feeds/categories/life.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ankursinha.in/</id><updated>2018-12-21T23:09:24+00:00</updated><subtitle>neuroscience/fedora/musings</subtitle><entry><title>On vacation</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2018/12/21/on-vacation.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-12-21T23:09:24+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-21T23:09:24+00:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2018-12-21:/2018/12/21/on-vacation.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;I will be on vacation for about 2 weeks with limited internet connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I will be on vacation till the start of the new year with limited internet
connectivity. I may not reply to e-mails until I return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy holidays!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Fedora"></category><category term="Planet"></category><category term="Holiday"></category></entry><entry><title>Cancelling my Times subscription - not as easy it should have been</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2016/11/27/cancelling-my-times-subscription-not-as-easy-it-should-have-been.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-27T22:33:36+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-27T22:33:36+00:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2016-11-27:/2016/11/27/cancelling-my-times-subscription-not-as-easy-it-should-have-been.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;If you're a Times subscriber, cancelling your subscription may be a bit of a trek.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'd signed up for a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.thetimes.co.uk/"&gt;Times subscription&lt;/a&gt; a few months ago. They had a 12£ for 12 weeks starter pack going around. Given that there's a lot free news out there, I don't really need to pay for news. It wasn't really for the news itself - it was for the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_polygon"&gt;Polygon&lt;/a&gt; puzzle that the Times do that I decided to subscribe. The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word_polygon"&gt;Polygon&lt;/a&gt; is an excellent vocabulary building puzzle that I thought would go rather well with our daily lunch time crossword. I didn't mind paying a pound a week for it. I'd set myself a reminder that I should cancel my subscription before 12 weeks were up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when the time finally came in August, I logged on to my Times account to see how I could cancel my subscription. There was very little information there. It gave a few phone numbers, and a chat link - but nothing directly pointed to how one can cancel. Fair enough, not the first website that doesn't make cancellation of subscriptions straight forward. I tried the chat first assuming the agent there would do it for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chatting to an agent usually solves things for me, whether it's Amazon, FitBit, or Charles Tyrwhitt, but not this time. The lady politely informed me that if I wished to cancel, I must use the phone. I was surprised by this - why &lt;em&gt;insist&lt;/em&gt; on using the phone? Anyway, I called immediately and found the automated phone system. Little did I know that there were a few surprises in store for me. Like most systems, the automated system provides a few options to choose from. In this case, though, there's a &lt;em&gt;specific&lt;/em&gt; option &amp;quot;to speak to the cancellation team&amp;quot;. Further, when one picks this choice, the automated voice reminds you that &amp;quot;this team only handles cancellations&amp;quot;. It made me wonder what the purpose of a specialised cancellation team was. Clearly, if the idea was to make it easy for people to cancel their subscriptions, a link on the website would be far more efficient? Even if they insisted on using the phone, an option that lets me cancel would work better too - but why set it up so that I must &lt;em&gt;speak&lt;/em&gt; to a &amp;quot;cancellation team&amp;quot; member?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these queries were soon answered. The cancellation team really are a specialised team. I spoke to this gentleman for about half an hour, and at no point was he willing to let me cancel my subscription. I just couldn't find a way around him! First, he made me give a reason - politely, of course, under the pretext of collecting feedback to improve their services. Naively, I fell for this tact. He'd keep offering me different packs - each &amp;quot;well tailored&amp;quot; to my requirements. Each reason I gave in an attempt to refuse a new pack was met with another suggestion! It was about ten minutes into the conversation that I accepted that the cancellation team were not in place to make it easy for users to cancel their subscriptions. How artless of me! On the contrary, they're there to make it as onerous as possible! This gentleman pleaded, made suggestion after suggestion, and in the end, offered to renew my 12£ for 12 weeks subscription as a last ditch attempt to keep me on the books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now, I was struggling to remain polite. I've known people that worked in customer service in the past. I know that they're usually given scripts to follow, and it is quite common that they get paid based on their success rate. So, I make it a point to be courteous when I interact with customer service agents. They're just doing their jobs, the way they've been asked to do them. Even here, I really did not want to have to resort to firmness or cost him some pay. Nevertheless, I hadn't expected a simple matter of cancelling a subscription to turn so incredibly arduous! Anyway, seeing no harm in keeping my quite cheap subscription, and telling myself that I could cancel in a few weeks, &lt;em&gt;I relented&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today. I was going through my credit card statements. I've been too busy to do my accounts of late. Today, I intended to clear out my backlog. While reconciling transactions, imagine the severe jolt I felt when I noticed that the Times had charged me 26£ each month for both September and October! That really was the last straw! It made me lose my temper and immediately log on to the my account to check what the status of my subscription was. The status still said &amp;quot;12£ for 12 weeks&amp;quot;! &amp;quot;Right, that's it, time to cancel my subscription and get rid of this headache once and for all&amp;quot;, I immediately thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried that chat again, and received the same response as the last time. Swiftly, I picked up my phone and made the call to the &amp;quot;cancellations team&amp;quot;. A Ben would handle my case and how could he help me today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;I'd like to cancel my subscription please.&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;Sure, can I have your details to pull up your account information?&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;Sure, here they are. Blah blah..&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;Before I process your cancellation, may I ask if it's to do with our services? I see that you have the digital pack. Are you able to use our services on the tablet, your phone, and the website? Which one do you prefer?&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;Gah, not again!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remained calm and with all the courtesy I could muster, I said that it had nothing to do with any services, that all I wanted was to &lt;em&gt;cancel my subscription&lt;/em&gt;. We did the same dance again, the only difference being that I was decisively steelier. I had made up my mind to get rid of the Times even if it required me to use a sterner tone. Again, I was offered multiple alternatives. I'm quite certain they're extremely well trained!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;No, I don't want any of those. I want to cancel &lt;em&gt;please&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fifteen minutes later, I was on the brink of a personal victory here. But, then!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;OK. I'll begin the cancellation process. Please hold on. ... Now, in our records I see that your contract is till the 7th of December. Per the terms of service, we require a fifteen day notice, so there will have to be one more charge of 26£ in December. Following that, your subscription will stop in January..&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was aghast! Completely speechless! Really? When I didn't respond, he went on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;.. or, we could switch you to a 2£ per week website only package?&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah! So that was the game? If the entire rigmarole wasn't enough to deter me, now it comes down to a form of blackmail? No, this wasn't going to fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;I'm happy to pay the 26£ but I want you to send me a written confirmation now that it will be the last I pay , and that my account will be closed thereafter.&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping a lid on my perplexed but upset self, I proceeded:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&amp;quot;I also want to point out that I was supposed to get an extension on my initial 12£ plan, but since you make us use the phone, I have no record of your colleague offering it to me. But, that's OK. Please cancel my account, send me the confirmation, and that's that.&amp;quot;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it was the guilt caused by the use of such a devious method, or simply the understanding that I wasn't going to extend my stay no matter what occurred, I cannot say, but he took a minute to check their records for a mention of said extension. Somehow, with me being extremely sceptical of any success, he did find the offer and went off to consult his his manager. When he returned, he apologised for the mistake. He said that since I'd been overcharged (52£ instead of 12£!), they would &amp;quot;make an exception&amp;quot; and cancel my subscription immediately without another charge. He would also refund the extra money they had charged. &amp;quot;Is this because they're afraid I'd complain to someone? Would this expose them to some liability?&amp;quot; it made me wonder but I was too weary to care too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, that is how I finally managed to rid myself of a news subscription. Writing about such occurrences has a therapeutic affect on me. It's usually in my journal, but I wanted to take the opportunity to inform other unsuspecting customers of the underhand practices that I've had to overcome for something as trivial as a 26£ a month subscription. I'm quite sure they aren't the only ones that use these tactics, so, before signing up for a new service, please do your research. It'll save you a lot of trouble later!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: Of course, the quotes may not be &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; what we said, but their tenor and general wording reflects my conversations accurately.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Subscriptions"></category><category term="The Times"></category><category term="Ethics"></category><category term="Underhand practices"></category></entry><entry><title>Learning to swim as an adult: Part I - Learning to not drown</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2015/10/25/learning-to-swim-as-an-adult-part-i-learning-to-not-drown.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-25T18:04:10+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-25T18:04:10+00:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2015-10-25:/2015/10/25/learning-to-swim-as-an-adult-part-i-learning-to-not-drown.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;I'm finally learning to swim!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;center&gt;&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Fireman_swimming_by_mimooh.svg"&gt;&lt;img alt="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Fireman_swimming_by_mimooh.svg that is under the `CC by SA 3.0 unported license &amp;lt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&amp;gt;`__." src="http://ankursinha.in/images/20151025-learning-to-swim-as-an-adult-i-learning-to-not-drown.png" style="height: 200.0px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Fireman_swimming_by_mimooh.svg"&gt;From wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; and under the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en"&gt;CC by SA 3.0 unported license&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;The facts to begin with. I'll turn 30 in a few years. I can't swim. Well, I couldn't even float till a fortnight ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="why"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me not knowing to swim has often come as quite a shock to a lot of the people that I've met in my life. More lately so since I moved out of a developing India to developed Australia and now England. It's quite common in India for someone to not know to swim. Quite a few people that live in land-locked areas, and a majority of India is land-locked, don't have access to swimming pools. The ones that do are generally too busy working or studying to ensure that they'll be employable when the time comes. Since a lot of parents don't swim themselves, they are unable to pass on the skill to their kids either. It's just a very different scenario to the one in developed countries where it's highly probable that even smaller towns will have swimming pools and the other infrastructure that goes with it. Of course, one can always say that these are all just excuses, but they're really not. You need to live the scenario to understand it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I did have a chance to learn to swim at boarding school. We had a small pool for kids that couldn't swim, and sometimes we even had an instructor that would try to teach us to swim. Here are my personal excuses for not making the most of this opportunity, and while none of them sound convincing enough, you need to remember that I was a stupid kid at this time - almost as stupid as I am today, maybe a little less even. Firstly, it was 30 of us crammed into a pool at a time, so it wasn't really the best environment to learn with kids barging into each other and all that sort of thing. Then, secondly, swimming season happened to fall during the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monsoon_of_South_Asia"&gt;Monsoons&lt;/a&gt;. To make this worse, so did Football season (we had the year divided into Cricket, Football and Hockey seasons and since neither Cricket nor Hockey can be played in the rain, it had to be Football during the rains). In the lower Himalayas, during the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monsoon_of_South_Asia"&gt;Monsoons&lt;/a&gt;, it generally rains weeks on end. Everything is wet and cold - it used to be so depressing that when the sun did finally come out, it prompted the head master to sometimes give us a &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;Sunshine Holiday&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; (&lt;em&gt;This most agreeable event was subtly announced by getting the chapel choir to sing &amp;quot;All things bright and beautiful&amp;quot; at the daily assembly, after which a teacher or another would come up and formally announce it - to lots of cheers and excitement, of course. I don't think the students were ever happier!&lt;/em&gt;). This already made the idea of spending time &lt;strong&gt;unclothed&lt;/strong&gt; in an &lt;strong&gt;outdoor unheated pool in the rain&lt;/strong&gt; quite unappealing. Add to that the thrill of playing Football with mates, and a land loving kid like me almost never gave swimming a thought. I did go down to the pool once or twice to be perfectly honest, but I didn't get too far. I could hold on to the side wall and paddle, but then everyone can do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing about not knowing how to swim, though, is that the older you get, the smaller the window of opportunity to learn gets. At school, there's the fact that your classmates will probably have a massive laugh at your expense when they see you flapping around in the water like a maniac - at boarding school, where you spend majority of your life with your classmates, &lt;em&gt;it's generally a good idea to keep embarrassing moments to a minimum&lt;/em&gt;. Unlike regular schools, you don't get to escape to mummy at the end of the day. Whatever it is, you face it there and then, possibly for days and nights afterwords. I don't mean this as a disadvantage of boarding schools at all, though. On the contrary, I prefer boarding schools any day - &lt;em&gt;you learn how to face everything that life can throw at you on your own, and that is a very very important skill to know - more important than swimming even&lt;/em&gt;. As you get older, other things come up too. For example, the Football you play gets more involved as it gets more structured and serious, since you begin to understand tactics and formations and all that sort of thing (When we were little, Football was more like a Brownian motion dictated by a Football - 20 kids kicking and chasing the ball around the park until somehow it ended up in the back of the net after beating a mostly bored and uninterested goalie). Your academics get harder and you need to spend a lot more time on your coursework. The number of co-curricular activities that you are expected to participate in increase - debates, elocutions, drama, clubs and societies, the choir even. Of course, then there's puberty that clobbers you mercilessly in the nuts with a spade and all sorts of relationshipy things begin to demand time - funnily enough, even if you aren't in a relationship. &lt;strong&gt;TLDR - lot busier, swimming not really that high up on the priority list.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="why-now"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow, learning how to swim has always been on my bucket list for a variety of reasons. Even though neither of my parents can swim themselves, they've always reminded me that it was something I needed to learn for myself. It was something they said they couldn't help me with, that it was my responsibility. I am also aware that swimming can be a most relaxing experience, and luckily, swimming is an exercise that covers all muscle groups too. Being in Europe also implies that a lot of my holidays nowadays are to sunlit beaches, and while I do venture into the water, I'd like to swim in it too. I missed out on this while I was in Sydney, but once I learn I do intend to head back down under and enjoy myself at the many beaches there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I received an e-mail that said that the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.activestudents.co.uk/"&gt;active students initiative&lt;/a&gt; were hosting a six week &amp;quot;swimming for dummies&amp;quot; course at very nominal prices - 25£ only - I really didn't have an excuse. I signed up right away, and even though the sessions began the next day which gave me very little time to prepare myself mentally, I did go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-first-class"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The first class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I was nervous. I got there about half an hour earlier than required and quietly sat in a corner preparing myself. I've never been scared of water - as long as I have at least a foot on the floor, that is. I've just never been confident enough to get both my feet off the pool's floor. &lt;em&gt;With six weeks to change that, I needed to convince myself that if I did let myself go in the water, I wouldn't encounter an excruciating death where water would fill my lungs until I'd maybe see my dead grandmother's ghost or something else that I didn't care for at all and then asphyxiate painfully to inadvertently but successfully prove the non existence of the afterlife to my non-existent self&lt;/em&gt;. To a swimmer, this almost sounds ridiculous - once you know how to float, you pretty much cannot drown - it becomes a sort of reflex. BUT, to someone who has never floated before, it really is a big deal. I could feel the adrenaline and I did the best to calm myself down. Even though there's oodles of logic out there that should easily convince me that I'd float, somehow, the trepidation wouldn't go away. The difficult thing about floating, which I now understand, is that you need to just let go - literally. So, in order to have some control over what you do in the water, you must first relinquish all control. I tried the usual tactics. I explained the physics of it to myself over and over. I've studied liquids and flotation in great detail at school - reminding myself of the concepts of buoyancy and displacement helped a bit. The next was reminding myself that I was an intelligent adult that was in the middle of his Ph.D. in neuroscience; one that loved Maths and found it fun even; one that did pretty well at most physical activities whether it was sprinting or Football; one that managed to pack up his life in India and move not once, but twice, to completely new continents. If the rest of the world, a majority of which seem to have a rather incomprehensible phobia of something as simple as Maths could figure out how to swim, surely I ruddy could too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the time to convert all this talk into action had come. I learned that there are 7 of us in the group - which is good. A smaller group means that the instructor can pay more attention to each of us individually. None of us could swim at all when we began, which was even better. We are all also in the same age group which was a relief to find out - all of us later confessed to being a bit worried that we'd be in class with little kids, which would be a bit embarrassing somehow. Being in the same boat as a few others calmed all our nerves down a bit, I'd think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing we were supposed to do was to try and float with the help of a long cylindrical floatation tube thing (I have no idea what it's called). The idea was to just let yourself go while holding the tube under your arms. The instructor kept telling us that we could trust him when he said the float would keep us from drowning. It took me a few minutes to try it out even. I kept standing on one leg trying to command myself to lift it off the floor. I tried a bit and went down, obviously, since you have to go down a bit to displace some water before you float (now I understand it!). Nope, foot back on the floor it is. A few more minutes and I finally convinced myself to trust a yellow coloured floating tube with my life. I basically relaxed and lay face down in the water - a bit of panic set in initially and I had this strong urge to cancel the attempt and put my foot down again. Somehow, and I really haven't a clue how, I kept leaning in until, almost like a miracle, I felt the water holding me up! Was I happy!! This was my Eureka moment - I was almost naked too! I tried it a few times to see if I'd gotten it right and in my excitement managed to gulp down a bit of the pool water - I'd forgotten the importance of &amp;quot;keep your mouth closed in the water&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sessions are each only 30 minutes long. For the rest of the first session, I tried to propel myself forward. Somehow, I kept turning to the right. Clearly lots of work to do there. I was also told that I need to work on my body shape a bit. I was trying to keep my head out of the water, which meant my back arched backwards. Not only does this make floating more difficult, it also gives you a back ache as I found out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I came out of the water really pleased with my progress. For a change, I was looking forward to the next session instead of dreading it. Funny how one experience can change your perspective about something so much!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-second-class"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The second class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second session was yesterday. Most of the group had returned. After the relative success of the first session, we'd have been stupid not to. It took me a few minutes to float again - even though I'd done it last week, doing it again was just a little scary (&amp;quot;I hope I haven't forgotten!&amp;quot;). Once I'd done that, the next was to try and float with my head inside the water - to improve on my body shape which would improve my technique and also spare me the back pain. Surprisingly, this didn't take much effort. After a bit, I was slowly moving forward with my head submerged - this was the first time I'd kept my eyes open under water long enough to see the pool floor move away backwards beneath me. This served as positive reinforcement and I was internally pleased with myself. I wanted to smile, but this time I was aware enough not to grin with my mouth open like I'd done last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instructor came over and gave me some pointers after a bit. Instead of kicking from the hip, I was kicking from the knee, for instance. Using the knees doesn't propel you as much as kicking from the hips would. The instructor said they call the correct technique &amp;quot;ballerina legs&amp;quot;. I worked on this finer side of myself for a bit - trying to propel myself forward while pointing my toes out and keeping my knees very straight - imagining myself to be delicate ballerina (not really!). I did get a lot further than I before. Then came the &lt;strong&gt;upgrade&lt;/strong&gt; - the instructor said I'd done enough to switch the big tube thing for two small rectangular floats which provided less support. Yay! I happily remarked that we'd probably be better off without knowing that detail on the less support. Again though, great timely positive reinforcement. I tried to do a bit without pausing - exhaling and inhaling while I propelled forward. I think I managed to do half a length before I gulped down some water(&lt;em&gt;again!&lt;/em&gt;) and had to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the instructor called time, we were all a bit disappointed. Since we'd been improving, we really wanted to spend more time in the water and practice our technique. Still, I think each one of us is a lot more confident in the water now, and for only two week's work, it's pretty great. Next week, we're going to learn how to use our arms - sort of getting started with the free style. As we walked back to the showers, we saw this little girl swim underwater and one of the guys jokingly went, &amp;quot;Look at her! The little show off!&amp;quot; - everyone broke into a laugh. Clearly, we'd begun enjoying ourselves!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion-it-s-all-in-the-head"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion - it's all in the head&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It really is. The way I approached it, it's a mental battle with oneself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have different goals in life. Mine, quite simply, is to keep improving - in whatever aspect I can, whether it's my research or my physical fitness. Sometimes you just need to wait for the right time, and the right chance. Of course, sometimes you'll take the chance but mess it up royally. I just messed up something amazing last night, and I've been kicking myself since and I expect to keep kicking myself for the next few months too. Hopefully, though, when I get another chance, and I will, I'll know better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning to swim was a big item on the bucket list, and now that I've initiated, I'm going to keep working on it until I'm a fairly strong swimmer. I have no intention to compete and all that, but if I can learn the strokes well enough to add a weekly swim session to my fitness regime, I think that'd be a pretty good result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To those who still can't swim, I hope this short tale will serve as encouragement and convince you to give it a good old fashioned try. All you pretty much need to do is float &lt;strong&gt;once&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I conclude, I must express my gratitude to our instructor, George, without whom none of us would've learned. He really knows what he's doing, and he knows how to get people to trust him enough to do what he asks. He also makes us feel safe in the water, which is paramount in the first few sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Social"></category><category term="Sports"></category><category term="Fedora"></category></entry><entry><title>Be careful: Not everyone is good</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2014/09/05/be-careful-not-everyone-is-good.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-09-05T17:27:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-09-05T17:27:00+01:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2014-09-05:/2014/09/05/be-careful-not-everyone-is-good.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;A horrid experience involving a giant, drunk, aggressive, foul mouthed racist.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've never written any thing personal on my blog. I reserve events
concerning my personal life for my friends, my family, my journal.
However, I post this event here to warn my friends in the Fedora
community. Most of you are like me - we want to be good people, not just
in our professional lives, but also in our personal lives. We want to be
the best we can be. We don't resort to violence, but at the same time we
don't get pushed around. This ordeal that I just experienced will tell
you that you need to be careful, even when you're trying to be a helpful
person. Sometimes it can get you into a dangerous corner, one that
could've been avoided if you were more sceptic like I generally am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-event-report"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The event report&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My sister and I had gone to Coles to get supplies for a normal weekend -
beer, food, the usual. On our way back,we got into the first gate of the
apartment complex using using the apartment key card. At this time,
there was this Aussie gentleman speaking to his cabby right outside the
gate. It’s about a hundred steps to the apartment door where you need to
swipe your key card again to get in to the main building. Before we’d
gotten in, this gentleman asked us to hold the first gate for him. This
isn’t uncommon. If there are a couple of people coming in, we hold the
gate for each other - we’re attempting to be good people here, to be
polite, social and helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we reached the second gate to the lower level where the lifts are,
this gentleman entered with us. When we finally got to the lift, we
asked him what floor he wanted to go to. This is also quite common. He
wanted to go to another floor - a floor that we don’t live on, and we
politely informed him that we didn’t have access to his floor - our key
cards only take the lift to our particular floors. By this time, we’d
noticed that he was quite drunk, the trousers of the suit he was in were
torn at the crotch, he couldn’t walk properly. My sister, still trying
to be a good, nice, polite, helpful person, took him out to the buzzer
and helped him call the apartment we thought he was living in. No one
answered. This is when he informed us that it was in fact his friends
flat, and that his friend was to leave him the key in the letter box. We
told him we couldn’t do much more, and it is when we tried to walk away,
that things got bad. He stepped between us and the door. He asked us if
he could &lt;strong&gt;pay to sleep at our place&lt;/strong&gt;. Now, you can be as helpful a
person as you want, but letting a complete stranger that is drunk out of
his wits sleep in your house is not something you’d do. If you would,
kudos, you’re..awesome? I don’t know. I can’t find a term that fits you
well enough. Anyway, we politely refused. My sister even said that there
was a kid at home to try and get him away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, this is when it gets really bad. He got aggressive. He kept saying
“Why? Why not?”, and we kept saying, “Sorry, we can’t. We just don’t
take people we don’t know into our home.” We then offered to get him to
a hotel and get him a cab to one. At this suggestion, he bellowed “Will
you f**king pay for the cab?”. Keeping my cool, I said that I’d be
happy to. I’d already understood that this “gentleman” wasn’t the best
person I’d met, and that somehow diffusing the situation and getting him
out of the compound would be the best result. Of course, he didn’t share
this view. He first abused us - he called us “cunts”, yes, “cunts”. Then
he went on to say “You f**king c**ts! You come here and eat up all
the taxes that we pay, and you can’t give me a place to f**king sleep
at night?”. Yeah right. All the tax we pay is just crap, right? He
pushed me against the wall, he kept abusing us, racial slurs, frequent
usage of the term “c**ts” and its synonyms, “I’ll f*king bash your
face in, you c**t.” and the sort. I was angry - I'm not violent, and I
don't resort to physical force until absolutely necessary, but I knew I
couldn’t react - it would just make matters worse. If I haven’t
mentioned already, this guy was huge. He was 6'3'' or more, well built.
Even when my brother in law came down, the two of us couldn’t have taken
his person physically. He kept abusing us for about 10 minutes. I'll let
you imagine what a drunk person fond of the word &amp;quot;c**t&amp;quot; is capable of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once my brother in law had come down, the two of us somehow managed to
calm him down and get him to agree going to a hotel. I’d called a cab
already. The operator warned me that the cabby may not drive this drunk
person, but I requested her to send one any way. We’d sent my sister up
already. This guy had abused her enough, and walked aggressively towards
her on a couple of occasions. When she was trying to talk to him, he
kept screaming “Keep your hands down you f**king c**t!”, and walking
towards her as if he would hit her. I'd put myself between the two to
make sure whatever he did didn’t get to her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our attempts to calm him down and get him out of the door, my brother
in law asked him to go out and check the letter box again. When my
brother in law checked it, he found the keys in there. This guy was so
drunk that he couldn’t find keys in an open letter box. We gave him the
keys and he went up to his friends flat and passed out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I called the police again. We weren't going to let this go just yet. The
police came about 20 minutes later. The operator told me that the police
needed to prioritise. Since I hadn't gotten hit, this case wasn't a
priority apparently. When the police came in, we told them what
happened. They called the apartment the guy had passed out in, but he
didn't wake. They couldn't get in, they left. They told us that since a
friend had left him the key, there wasn't much they could do.
Additionally, since no one had been beaten to death, the most they could
do was to talk to this person. Great. If you manage to escape the
situation in one piece, the police can't take action. So, should I have
pissed this person off to get him to gaol? Does he have to kill someone
to be punished? I don't know. We were just disappointed that the police
didn't do much. Of course, it did occur to me that us being Indians in
Australia had something to do with this, but it's wrong of me to state
it. I don't know another similar case when Aussies had reported it, and
I don't know what the police did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, I got out of a bad situation without getting my teeth out on the
floor like my weekend shopping. Great experience eh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="my-take"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My take&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a born Hindu, one of the things we're taught is &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;If you do good
things, good things will happen to you.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; Well, so much for that. We
were trying to be nice, and we almost got our faces bashed in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pay our taxes, so no, we're not leeching off Aussies. We pay our way.
In fact, I paid 50,000 AUD for my 4 semesters at UTS as an international
student. So, please, if you have ignorant friends who think we
&amp;quot;immigrants&amp;quot;, as we're popularly referred to, are leeching off your
money, please educate them. We study, we earn, we pay our taxes, we pay
for everything we do. We don't take Aussie money for anything we do. If
you think we shouldn't be taking your jobs, well then, study up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event is more significant to me than it would normally be. I'm not
shaken up. I'm really not scared of getting beaten up. At least that
would've gotten this guy into gaol and probably saved the next guy that
shan't be as lucky. A couple of weeks back, when I still lived at
university housing, a drunk lady had come up to me to ask me for
something. I, as a rule, avoid drunk people. Don't get me wrong, I drink
too - and quite a bit when I'm with friends. However, I'm never out of
control, and I've never had to ask a stranger for help. I ignored her
and walked away. She screamed something about a gentleman to which I
mentally replied &amp;quot;Yeah, real lady you are, walking around drunk on the
streets.&amp;quot; However, when I thought about it later in the confines of my
hostel room, I thought I could've done better. I could've helped her. So
what if she was drunk? May be she did really need help. I felt guilty
and I'd modified my rule to &amp;quot;Help people, believe that people are good.&amp;quot;
It's why I decided to help this person in the first place. Now, after
this experience, I'm not so certain if I'd made a change for the better
or worse. Had I walked away, I wouldn't have gotten pushed around, or
abused, or racially abused. I know that I shouldn't generalise on the
basis of this one experience, but it isn't right to generalise on the
basis of good experiences either - even I've had quite a few of them.
The one thing you can't ignore is that one bad experience might leave
you with a life long injury. Is it really worth it? What if this person
had hit me? What then? What if he had hit my sister? What then? What if
he had hit us hard enough to cause us permanent injury? Just because it
didn't happen doesn't mean that it couldn't. When he was pushing me
around, I wasn't thinking of &amp;quot;God&amp;quot; teaching me a lesson. Everything is a
lesson in hindsight if you survive it. Not everyone is that lucky
though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not helping drunk people any more. Until I know for sure that
someone's worth helping, I'm going to be my normal sceptic self. You may
or may not agree with my decision, and it's yours to make. Please just
remember, that whatever you do, your safety is most important. There are
better ways of helping strangers than stepping into a situation that
might result in you losing teeth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>How I got my first (semi) black eye</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2012/03/21/how-i-got-my-first-semi-black-eye.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-03-21T00:25:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-03-21T00:25:00+00:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2012-03-21:/2012/03/21/how-i-got-my-first-semi-black-eye.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear life,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got hit in the eye with a squash ball earlier today. I was trying to
coach a tyro. I'm grateful for the positive reinforcement you give me
when I make an effort to help people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yours,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ankur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear life,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got hit in the eye with a squash ball earlier today. I was trying to
coach a tyro. I'm grateful for the positive reinforcement you give me
when I make an effort to help people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yours,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ankur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Sports"></category></entry><entry><title>My first ever parking ticket</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2011/01/14/my-first-ever-parking-ticket.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-14T10:17:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-01-14T10:17:00+00:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2011-01-14:/2011/01/14/my-first-ever-parking-ticket.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post is not fedora related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas! I have failed to maintain my clean sheet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that came to mind on noticing the missing vehicle was
&amp;quot;God! It's been stolen!&amp;quot;. Such an event occurring early in my life at
Bangalore wouldn't have fit into my plans at all …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post is not fedora related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas! I have failed to maintain my clean sheet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that came to mind on noticing the missing vehicle was
&amp;quot;God! It's been stolen!&amp;quot;. Such an event occurring early in my life at
Bangalore wouldn't have fit into my plans at all. It wouldn't have aided
in digestion either. &amp;nbsp;An environment of panic followed before more
people turned up with similar confused countenances. Then, an auto
driver informed us that this was a &amp;quot;No parking zone&amp;quot; after the shops had
closed and that our bikes had been towed away to the nearest police
station. Weirdly enough, I had searched the location for a sign that
said either &amp;quot;Tow away zone&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;No parking&amp;quot; and had failed to find one.
I am very particular (or very scared) about such things. Well, what can
one do? Nothing! You take a cab to the police station, pay the INR 300
fine and recollect your bike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 300 INR fine actually was quite a relief compared to a stolen bike. A
lesson learnt : &amp;quot;A no parking zone implies you cannot park your vehicle
there. However, the absence of a sign does not give you the permission
to do so. Only park where you find a parking sign, not where you find
parked vehicles. They'd all get towed away!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Bangalore"></category></entry><entry><title>Keep your cool. Always.</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2010/11/09/keep-your-cool-always.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-11-09T13:50:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-11-09T13:50:00+00:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2010-11-09:/2010/11/09/keep-your-cool-always.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Declaration: This post is not directed at any one person in particular.
It's a general statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a much newer contributor to Fedora than most people I know. I only
began contributing to Fedora after Fedora 8 was released (when I signed
up as a font package maintainer ). I had …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Declaration: This post is not directed at any one person in particular.
It's a general statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm a much newer contributor to Fedora than most people I know. I only
began contributing to Fedora after Fedora 8 was released (when I signed
up as a font package maintainer ). I had never been part of such a huge
voluntary community that does excellent work before then (I turned 22
this year ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, the number of mailing lists I try to follow has grown
quite a bit. Now I have about 25 folders in my Evolution client
dedicated to different Fedora mailing lists. I don't go through all the
mails, but pick and choose what threads seem like stuff I'd need to
know. 25 mailing lists means a lot of discussion, a lot of people, a lot
of points of view and a lot of different moods/tones in which people
respond to queries/mails. This post is about the last one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fedora has a guideline which goes &amp;quot;be excellent to each other&amp;quot;. I've had
to remind folks of this at multiple occasions now. It's not a random
guideline, it has reason behind it. I'll enumerate a few:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mailing list has not been set up so you can vent out a bad day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you need someone's help, being rude to him/her is really not going
to get you much in return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's contagious! Once a rude discussion begins, more and more people
leave constructive work to jump in with their points of view!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gets nothing done. Ultimately, the thread ends with someone going,
&amp;quot;let's calm it down a bit, mate&amp;quot;. The actual purpose of the thread is
forgotten because so much discussion over tones took place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It makes people who actually want to work ignore the thread. Even
less chances of any work being done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When team mates, community members bicker amongst themselves, the
entire community gets laughed at. You might not care, but some of us
do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you should be doing when you reply to a mail:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand what the thread is about. Replying without anything
constructive is a waste of resources. Longer threads get less work
done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you're angry, go take a walk. Calm down. Think it through. Even if
someone's been rude to you, a stern reply won't change anything. In
fact, you'll end up privately mailing each other, wasting each
other's valuable time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to ignore personal comments. All of us are mature enough to
filter out the personal remarks and harsh tones and only pick up the
important portions of an email. If an email is only personal remarks
and tones, delete it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-read your email twice before you send it. Is it too aggressive? Is
it just too much useless talk? Is there an unnecessary personal
comment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom line here is that decorum should be maintained over a mailing
list. We are all friends, but tones and feelings need other channels of
exchange, a mailing list is not one.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Community"></category></entry></feed>