<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>ankursinha.in/blog - Bangalore</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ankursinha.in//feeds/tags/bangalore.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ankursinha.in/</id><updated>2011-01-14T10:17:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>My first ever parking ticket</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2011/01/14/my-first-ever-parking-ticket.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-01-14T10:17:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-01-14T10:17:00+00:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2011-01-14:/2011/01/14/my-first-ever-parking-ticket.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post is not fedora related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas! I have failed to maintain my clean sheet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that came to mind on noticing the missing vehicle was
&amp;quot;God! It's been stolen!&amp;quot;. Such an event occurring early in my life at
Bangalore wouldn't have fit into my plans at all …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post is not fedora related.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas! I have failed to maintain my clean sheet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that came to mind on noticing the missing vehicle was
&amp;quot;God! It's been stolen!&amp;quot;. Such an event occurring early in my life at
Bangalore wouldn't have fit into my plans at all. It wouldn't have aided
in digestion either. &amp;nbsp;An environment of panic followed before more
people turned up with similar confused countenances. Then, an auto
driver informed us that this was a &amp;quot;No parking zone&amp;quot; after the shops had
closed and that our bikes had been towed away to the nearest police
station. Weirdly enough, I had searched the location for a sign that
said either &amp;quot;Tow away zone&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;No parking&amp;quot; and had failed to find one.
I am very particular (or very scared) about such things. Well, what can
one do? Nothing! You take a cab to the police station, pay the INR 300
fine and recollect your bike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 300 INR fine actually was quite a relief compared to a stolen bike. A
lesson learnt : &amp;quot;A no parking zone implies you cannot park your vehicle
there. However, the absence of a sign does not give you the permission
to do so. Only park where you find a parking sign, not where you find
parked vehicles. They'd all get towed away!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Bangalore"></category></entry></feed>