<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>ankursinha.in/blog - Gitter</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ankursinha.in/feeds/tags/gitter.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ankursinha.in/</id><updated>2017-07-12T13:55:17+01:00</updated><subtitle>neuroscience/fedora/musings</subtitle><entry><title>Bringing together Gitter, IRC, and Slack channels in one place on Riot</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2017/07/12/bringing-together-gitter-irc-and-slack-channels-in-one-place-on-riot.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-12T13:55:17+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-12T13:55:17+01:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2017-07-12:/2017/07/12/bringing-together-gitter-irc-and-slack-channels-in-one-place-on-riot.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Different teams use different platforms to communicate within themselves. When teams on different communication platforms want to collaborate, though - there's a bit of an issue. In this post, I document how one can setup channels on various platforms (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slack.com"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitter.im"&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt;) and bring them all together on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="let-s-not-let-our-choice-of-platform-limit-us"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let's not let our choice of platform limit us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are usually multiple platforms that provide similar functions. For instance, one can pick between &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitlab.com"&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bitbucket.com"&gt;BitBucket&lt;/a&gt; for collaborative development interfaces, and one certainly should have the freedom to do so. Similarly, one can use different operating systems, web browsers, phones, etc etc etc. But, one must remember is that for a lot of us, these are simply means to an end - not the end themselves. They are tools that facilitate the completion of our goals. Different individuals or teams preferring different platforms should not hamper collaboration under any circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to communcation, different teams use different platforms. Some prefer e-mails - either private or using a mailing list. E-mails work well, but they're often overkill for simpler tasks. They're also not the best mode for quick collaborative development. This is where real-time chat comes in. Most open source communities maintain both mailing lists and chat infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to chat platforms too, there are multiple options. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitter.im"&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; are designed to handle large communities and are therefore, usually preferred by open source communities. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slack.com"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; seems to be preferred by smaller teams. There are others - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://mattermost.com"&gt;Mattermost&lt;/a&gt;, for example, but I haven't much experience with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, I've found people wary of hopping on to a different platform simply because it's too much work to set up yet another client that one must then also monitor. While this is understandable, it then has what I consider quite a major downside - limited communication amongst groups that are on different platforms. Fortunately, most platforms support bridges which lets the user connect them with other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="riot-bringing-it-all-together-in-once-place"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Riot - bringing it all together in once place&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170628-riot.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Using riot to access IRC, Slack, and Gitter" class="text-center img-responsive pagination-centered" src="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170628-riot.png" style="width: 70%;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; is an Open source platform that uses the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://matrix.org/"&gt;Matrix&lt;/a&gt; protocol. It's similar to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, but it's a lot more usable. and what is better, one can integrate &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slack.com"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitter.im"&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt; into &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; - so one can interact with users over all these platforms in one place. For example, the image below shows &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im/app/#/room/%23neuroscience-central-lobby:matrix.org"&gt;Neuroscience-central/Lobby&lt;/a&gt; room  that I've set up on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;. But, I've also gone ahead and connected this room to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitter.im/neuroscience-central/Lobby"&gt;Neuroscience-central/Lobby room on Gitter&lt;/a&gt;, and to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=#neuroscience-central-lobby"&gt;#neuroscience-central-lobby channel on IRC&lt;/a&gt;. So, everyone on any of these platforms can communicate with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170628-riot-gitter.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Neuroscience-Central/Lobby on Riot integrated with the same room on Gitter." class="text-center img-responsive pagination-centered" src="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170628-riot-gitter.png" style="width: 70%;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting up the integrations is rather easy too. One needs to go to the integrations tab and set them up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170628-riot-integrations.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Integrations on Riot" class="text-center img-responsive pagination-centered" src="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170628-riot-integrations.png" style="width: 70%;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im/desktop.html"&gt;desktop clients&lt;/a&gt; available for &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; too. (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://copr.fedorainfracloud.org/coprs/taw/Riot/"&gt;Here's a COPR for Fedora&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://opensource.com/article/17/5/introducing-riot-IRC"&gt;Here's a great post on opensource.com&lt;/a&gt; discussing &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you're an admin looking to set up a new chat channel - consider setting up on different platforms and integrating them with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; - it'll make things a lot easier for your users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Community"></category><category term="Computational neuroscience"></category><category term="Fedora"></category><category term="FlatPak"></category><category term="Free software"></category><category term="Gitter"></category><category term="Linux"></category><category term="Planet"></category></entry><entry><title>A channel for neuroscientists on Gitter</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2017/06/26/a-channel-for-neuroscientists-on-gitter.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-26T10:30:01+01:00</published><updated>2017-06-26T10:30:01+01:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2017-06-26:/2017/06/26/a-channel-for-neuroscientists-on-gitter.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;I've come across a few mailing lists for neuroscientists, but I couldn't find a chat channel. While mailing lists suit certain purposes, open source communities tend to use a combination of mailing lists and chat channels - each platform serves different purposes. TLDR: here's a new chat channel on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gitterHQ"&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitter.im/neuroscience-central/Lobby"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for everything neuroscience related. It is also accessible using the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=#neuroscience-central-lobby"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im/app/#/room/#neuroscience-central-lobby:matrix.org"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As opposed to the free software community, where I've been around long enough to know what's where, I'm still relatively new to the neuroscience community. Over the two years that I've been doing my PhD, I've found a few neuroscience related mailing lists, but not any chat channels. Various teams tend to use &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slack.com/"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; or another platform for internal communications, but nothing seems to be set up for the community in general - an open for all channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mailing lists are extremely useful, but by design they are suited to particular types of tasks. They are very well suited for longer discussions, and general queries that are not time sensitive, for example. On the other hand, they do not work well for urgent queries, and of course, sometimes sending e-mails back and forth is quite an overhead for simpler tasks or collaborative development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most open source communities have both mailing lists and chat channels. I figured it'd be nice to have one for the neuroscience community too. There's the question of what platform was best suited, of course. We use &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slack.com/"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; for our internal communication, but &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slack.com/"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; only works well for small teams. It isn't designed for larger communities. The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt; is ideal for larger communities, but on the flip side, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt; is not very user friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third option, and the popular alternative to IRC and Slack, is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gitterHQ"&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt; - it's been recently &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://about.gitlab.com/2017/03/15/gitter-acquisition/"&gt;acquired by GitLab&lt;/a&gt; and will be completely open sourced soon. It's completely free to use unlike &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slack.com/"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; where one needs to pay more as the number of group members increases, and is designed for large communities that number in the thousands. One can login using either Github or Twitter - so that's quite convenient too. There's even an &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://irc.gitter.im/"&gt;IRC gateway&lt;/a&gt; for more technical users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here's the channel then - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitter.im/neuroscience-central/Lobby"&gt;https://gitter.im/neuroscience-central/Lobby&lt;/a&gt;. I hope it'll be useful, and if it doesn't, well no harm done :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update (12 July 2017):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enable people to communicate over various platforms, I've also set the channel up with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;. This enables people using &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gitterHQ"&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ankursinha.in/2017/07/12/bringing-together-gitter-irc-and-slack-channels-in-one-place-on-riot.html"&gt;communicate with each other in one place using whatever platform they prefer&lt;/a&gt;. So, we also have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=#neuroscience-central-lobby"&gt;#neuroscience-central-lobby&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im/app/#/room/#neuroscience-central-lobby:matrix.org"&gt;neuroscience-central/Lobby&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content><category term="Community"></category><category term="Computational neuroscience"></category><category term="Gitter"></category><category term="Planet"></category></entry></feed>