<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>ankursinha.in/blog - NPP</title><link href="https://ankursinha.in/" rel="alternate"/><link href="https://ankursinha.in/feeds/tags/npp.atom.xml" rel="self"/><id>https://ankursinha.in/</id><updated>2024-06-21T13:16:43+01:00</updated><subtitle>neuroscience/fedora/musings</subtitle><entry><title>Week 25 update</title><link href="https://ankursinha.in/2024/06/21/week-25-update.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2024-06-21T13:16:43+01:00</published><updated>2024-06-21T13:16:43+01:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2024-06-21:/2024/06/21/week-25-update.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Weekly update to week #25&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="neuroml-related"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;NeuroML related&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="NeuroML is a standard and software ecosystem for biophysically detailed neuronal modelling." class="text-center img-responsive pagination-centered" src="https://ankursinha.in/images/neuroml-logo.png" style="width: 40%;" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://neuroml.org"&gt;NeuroML&lt;/a&gt; is a standard and software ecosystem for biophysically detailed neuronal modelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made new releases of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/NeuroML/jNeuroML"&gt;jNeuroML&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/NeuroML/pyNeuroML"&gt;pyNeuroML&lt;/a&gt;.
The new releases allow users to keep their &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.neuroml.org/Userdocs/Schemas/Cells.html#morphology"&gt;morphology&lt;/a&gt; in separate files and &amp;quot;include&amp;quot; these in cell files.
The use case here is that when investigating neuronal biophysics, it would be useful to not have to repeat the morphology each time the cell is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also updated our &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.neuroml.org/Userdocs/ImportingMorphologyFiles.html#neuroml2"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; to note this new feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="google-summer-of-code"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Google Summer of Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aditya and Ioannis have both completed their first tasks and their pull requests are ready for review.
I'll try and review them next week.
In the meantime, they've got new tasks for next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="model-conversion"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Model conversion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still working on the converting the two remaining Calcium channels in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.cell.com/cell-reports/fulltext/S2211-1247(18)31088-X"&gt;Zang et al&lt;/a&gt;.
They're slightly trickier to convert because of the formalism they follow, but I should get there with another few days of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ucl"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;UCL&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.ucl.ac.uk/research/domains/neuroscience/events/neuroscience-symposia"&gt;UCL Neuroscience symposium&lt;/a&gt; was on Thursday.
The talks and posters were great and very informative, e.g.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on visual processing (using &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-019-00791-w"&gt;really cool virtual reality experiments&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on the role of sleep on synapses numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dementia with particular focus on Alzheimer's disease and the role of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tau_protein"&gt;tau protein&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd also had a really interesting talk on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glucagon-like_peptide-1"&gt;GLP-1 receptor&lt;/a&gt;, which is involved in the secretion of insulin for maintenance of blood sugar levels, at our &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.ucl.ac.uk/biosciences/neuroscience-physiology-and-pharmacology"&gt;Neuroscience, Pharmacology, and Physiology (NPP)&lt;/a&gt; departmental seminar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also involved with the mentoring programme that the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.ucl.ac.uk/biosciences/"&gt;Division of Biosciences&lt;/a&gt; runs for PhD students.
We had discussed this at the divisional meeting last week, and now we have a few tasks to carry out to improve the programme's reach to more students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ocns"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;OCNS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="The annual conference of the Organization for Computational Neurosciences will happen in July in Natal, Brazil, this year." class="text-center img-responsive pagination-centered" src="https://ankursinha.in/images/2024-cns-2024-banner.png" style="width: 60%;" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;The annual conference of the Organization for Computational Neurosciences will happen in July in Natal, Brazil, this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm organising the career development workshop at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.cnsorg.org/cns-2024-quick"&gt;annual conference&lt;/a&gt; of the Organization for Computational Neuroscience as part of my Board member responsibilities.
This year, we're hosting a &amp;quot;beyond academia&amp;quot; session where we'll have folks who have worked or are currently working in industry after their doctorates and initial academic positions will speak about their experiences.
The goal is to discuss careers that academics can take up outside of the traditional academic research domain.
With help from a number of Board members and others at the lab at UCL, I had a list of people to reach out to.
We now have a panel of four, so we're on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The programme for the conference is also now online on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cns2024.sched.com/"&gt;Sched&lt;/a&gt;, and registration is still open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had a quick meeting with the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.cnsorg.org/board-of-directors"&gt;OCNS EDI chair&lt;/a&gt;, Eirini Mavristaki, about the mentoring programme that the OCNS is trying to set up for its members.
Eirini has already got most of it ready, and I'll help with the remaining bits to try and launch it at the conference or soon after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="fedora-related"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fedora related&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few of us contributors met for a catch up last evening.
We met in Soho, had a few drinks and then had a great meal in Chinatown.
We organise these on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://matrix.to/#/#region-uk:fedoraproject.org"&gt;Fedora UK matrix channel&lt;/a&gt;, so if you're interested in joining us for the next meetup, please drop in there and let us know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://neuro.fedoraproject.org"&gt;NeuroSIG&lt;/a&gt; meeting on Monday.
We went through our packages and so on.
They look fine.
A few are broken after the Python 3.13 mass re-build but as more and more packages are fixed, a lot of our packages should also start to build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Life"/><category term="NeuroML"/><category term="Computational Neuroscience"/><category term="Fedora"/><category term="GSoC"/><category term="UCL"/><category term="NPP"/><category term="Biosciences"/></entry></feed>