<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>ankursinha.in/blog - Planet</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ankursinha.in//feeds/tags/planet.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ankursinha.in/</id><updated>2017-10-07T14:19:10+01:00</updated><entry><title>Fedora Classroom: Git 101: report</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2017/10/07/fedora-classroom-git-101-report.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-07T14:19:10+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-07T14:19:10+01:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2017-10-07:/2017/10/07/fedora-classroom-git-101-report.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;I taught a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Classroom"&gt;Fedora Classroom&lt;/a&gt; session the other day - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://meetbot.fedoraproject.org/fedora-classroom/2017-10-05/fedora-classroom.2017-10-05-14.17.log.html"&gt;Git 101&lt;/a&gt; -
where I walked through the basics of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://git-scm.com/"&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;. This is a quick summary
of the session.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I taught another &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Classroom"&gt;Fedora Classroom&lt;/a&gt; this week, on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://meetbot.fedoraproject.org/fedora-classroom/2017-10-05/fedora-classroom.2017-10-05-14.17.log.html"&gt;Git 101&lt;/a&gt;. I used the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;
again since this session was to be another hands-on walkthrough. I reckon I've
now learned that hands-on sessions go on longer than initially planned. This
one lasted about three hours!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="some-metrics"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some metrics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Length: 3 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attendees: ~25 people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sentences spoken: LOTS!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="summary"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't go much into the theory, and there's a lot of it in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://git-scm.com/"&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, I
had made it my goal to walk the attendees through the usual &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://git-scm.com/"&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; workflow.
So, that's exactly what we did. We started by setting up an empty repository,
then added files to it, learned how to see changes and so on. Then, we moved
on to branching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we'd explored the advantages of using branches we started working with
remotes. Everyone set up repositories on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pagure.io"&gt;Pagure&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. To end with, I
got everyone to fork my repository and submit pull requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think everyone got the hang of it. There were some good questions, a bit of
discussion too. I do hope it'll get more people to use &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://git-scm.com/"&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; and contribute to
different projects on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pagure.io"&gt;Pagure&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="feedback-is-always-welcome"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Feedback is always welcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you had attended the session, or have gone through the logs and have some
feedback, please get in touch. You can use the Fedora classroom channels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:classroom&amp;#64;lists.fedoraproject.org"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#fedora-classroom on Freenode &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=%23fedora-classroom"&gt;IRC channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can even comment on this blog post, and of course, you can give me feedback
privately. I'm FranciscoD on quite a few Fedora IRC channels, and I can be
reached via e-mail on my Fedora address at ankursinha AT fedoraproject DOT org.
All suggestions, comments, criticism is most welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-instructors-needed"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More instructors needed!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The classroom sessions are going rather well, but &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Classroom#Help_wanted"&gt;we still need more help&lt;/a&gt;. We'd like to cover
more topics from different areas, not just tech related- everything from
design, to free software philosophy and community building! If there's anything
at all you think is worth a classroom session, please get in touch with the
team on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:classroom&amp;#64;lists.fedoraproject.org"&gt;Fedora classroom mailing list&lt;/a&gt;. A log of all past sessions -
whether on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt; or on a video platform are maintained on the wiki page &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Classroom#Previous_Sessions"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for everyone to
peruse at their convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="logs"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Logs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://meetbot.fedoraproject.org/fedora-classroom/2017-10-05/fedora-classroom.2017-10-05-14.17.log.html"&gt;HTML logs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://meetbot.fedoraproject.org/fedora-classroom/2017-10-05/fedora-classroom.2017-10-05-14.17.html"&gt;HTML minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://meetbot.fedoraproject.org/fedora-classroom/2017-10-05/fedora-classroom.2017-10-05-14.17.txt"&gt;Text minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Community"></category><category term="Fedora"></category><category term="Git"></category><category term="Planet"></category></entry><entry><title>Fedora Classroom: Command Line 101: report</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2017/08/10/fedora-classroom-command-line-101-report.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-10T23:03:24+01:00</published><updated>2017-08-10T23:03:24+01:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2017-08-10:/2017/08/10/fedora-classroom-command-line-101-report.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;I taught a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Classroom"&gt;Fedora classroom&lt;/a&gt; session today - &amp;quot;Command Line 101&amp;quot; - where I introduced the command line and demonstrated how useful the command line is. This is a quick summary of the session.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We've gotten the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Classroom"&gt;Fedora classroom&lt;/a&gt; sessions going again. After two really good ones, I taught the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fedoramagazine.org/fedora-classroom-session-3/"&gt;third one&lt;/a&gt; today - a beginners session to the command line. Unlike the previous ones that used video platforms, I decided that the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt; was best suited to this session, even more so because I wanted it to be a hands-on session. It went off pretty well. Here are a few notes. Links to the logs are at the bottom of this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="some-metrics"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some metrics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Length: 2 hours (was planned to be an hour, but we quickly realised that it wouldn't be enough!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attendees: 29 - a few of us had FAS usernames too (so we shared cookies!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About 800 sentences were spoken (I spoke about half of these, of course)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="summary"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quite enjoyed it, but then I enjoy tinkering with the command line anyway. A few folks stuck around for the full two hours, so that does indicate that they found the session somewhat useful. I'd put up a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gist.github.com/sanjayankur31/f40070c6925e8885394d2dd750ae4cb8"&gt;gist here with a tentative agenda&lt;/a&gt;. We didn't manage to go more than half way through it, though. We:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;did a quick introduction to what a shell is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learned how to get help using local information - using the man pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quickly saw the difference between absolute and relative paths, and also learned about &lt;code&gt;..&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;went on to look at some more basic commands/built-ins and their switches/flags/options: &lt;code&gt;ls, apropos, clear, cd, pwd, which, alias, rm, tree, mkdir, wget, rmdir, rm, fpaste, wc, head, tail, more, less, cat, tac, grep, sort, uniq&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;used these commands to download a copy of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.gutenberg.org/cache/epub/1120/pg1120.txt"&gt;&amp;quot;The tragedy of Julius Caesar&amp;quot; from Project Gutenberg&lt;/a&gt;, and then extracted some information from it. For example, we obtained how many times Caesar was mentioned in the text. For a more advanced task we also obtained how many times Caesar, Brutus, Cassius, and Casca were each mentioned using a single set of commands. This required the use of &lt;code&gt;grep, sort, uniq, wc&lt;/code&gt; in different combinations using input-output redirection (pipes in this case). At no point did we use a text editor, and we stuck to using local man pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="takeaways"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that this rather quick session gave the participants some idea of how the shell can be used for lots of tasks. I also hoped to show them that there's a lot of information available on the system itself that a user can refer to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned a few things myself. I learned that an hour is too short for a proper online session, for example. My supposition that demonstrating commands using tasks would make the session more appealing seems to have been correct too. Only, maybe next time I'll pick a more contemporary text?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the next session, I'll try and cover slightly more advanced topics, such as tests, loops, maybe even a bit of awk. We shall see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="feedback-is-always-welcome"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Feedback is always welcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you had attended the session, or have gone through the logs and have some feedback, please get in touch. You can use the Fedora classroom channels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:classroom&amp;#64;lists.fedoraproject.org"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#fedora-classroom on Freenode &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=%23fedora-classroom"&gt;IRC channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can even comment on this blog post, and of course, you can give me feedback privately. I'm also looking to make a list of tasks that I can use in future sessions - tasks that would be useful, fun, and that would also require some command line tricks - such that they would demonstrate the power of the command line. So, if you have your pet command line tricks/aliases, please do get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm FranciscoD on quite a few Fedora IRC channels, and I can be reached via e-mail on my Fedora address at ankursinha AT fedoraproject DOT org. All suggestions, comments, criticism is most welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-instructors-needed"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More instructors needed!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The classroom sessions are going rather well, but &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Classroom#Help_wanted"&gt;we still need more help&lt;/a&gt;. We need more people helping with logistics, and of course, if we are to continue these sessions every week, we need more instructors! If there's anything at all you think is worth a classroom session, please get in touch with the team on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:classroom&amp;#64;lists.fedoraproject.org"&gt;Fedora classroom mailing list&lt;/a&gt;. A log of all past sessions - whether on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt; or on a video platform are maintained on the wiki page &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Classroom#Previous_Sessions"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for everyone to peruse at their convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="logs"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Logs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://meetbot.fedoraproject.org/fedora-classroom/2017-08-10/%22fedora_classroom_-_command_line_101%22.2017-08-10-13.00.log.html"&gt;HTML logs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://meetbot.fedoraproject.org/fedora-classroom/2017-08-10/%22fedora_classroom_-_command_line_101%22.2017-08-10-13.00.txt"&gt;Text minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://meetbot.fedoraproject.org/fedora-classroom/2017-08-10/%22fedora_classroom_-_command_line_101%22.2017-08-10-13.00.html"&gt;HTML minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Bash"></category><category term="Blog"></category><category term="Community"></category><category term="Linux"></category><category term="Planet"></category><category term="Fedora"></category></entry><entry><title>Bringing together Gitter, IRC, and Slack channels in one place on Riot</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2017/07/12/bringing-together-gitter-irc-and-slack-channels-in-one-place-on-riot.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-12T13:55:17+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-12T13:55:17+01:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2017-07-12:/2017/07/12/bringing-together-gitter-irc-and-slack-channels-in-one-place-on-riot.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Different teams use different platforms to communicate within themselves. When teams on different communication platforms want to collaborate, though - there's a bit of an issue. In this post, I document how one can setup channels on various platforms (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slack.com"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitter.im"&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt;) and bring them all together on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="let-s-not-let-our-choice-of-platform-limit-us"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let's not let our choice of platform limit us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are usually multiple platforms that provide similar functions. For instance, one can pick between &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitlab.com"&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bitbucket.com"&gt;BitBucket&lt;/a&gt; for collaborative development interfaces, and one certainly should have the freedom to do so. Similarly, one can use different operating systems, web browsers, phones, etc etc etc. But, one must remember is that for a lot of us, these are simply means to an end - not the end themselves. They are tools that facilitate the completion of our goals. Different individuals or teams preferring different platforms should not hamper collaboration under any circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to communcation, different teams use different platforms. Some prefer e-mails - either private or using a mailing list. E-mails work well, but they're often overkill for simpler tasks. They're also not the best mode for quick collaborative development. This is where real-time chat comes in. Most open source communities maintain both mailing lists and chat infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to chat platforms too, there are multiple options. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitter.im"&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; are designed to handle large communities and are therefore, usually preferred by open source communities. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slack.com"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; seems to be preferred by smaller teams. There are others - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://mattermost.com"&gt;Mattermost&lt;/a&gt;, for example, but I haven't much experience with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, I've found people wary of hopping on to a different platform simply because it's too much work to set up yet another client that one must then also monitor. While this is understandable, it then has what I consider quite a major downside - limited communication amongst groups that are on different platforms. Fortunately, most platforms support bridges which lets the user connect them with other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="riot-bringing-it-all-together-in-once-place"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Riot - bringing it all together in once place&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170628-riot.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Using riot to access IRC, Slack, and Gitter" class="text-center img-responsive pagination-centered" src="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170628-riot.png" style="width: 70%;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; is an Open source platform that uses the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://matrix.org/"&gt;Matrix&lt;/a&gt; protocol. It's similar to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, but it's a lot more usable. and what is better, one can integrate &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slack.com"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitter.im"&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt; into &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; - so one can interact with users over all these platforms in one place. For example, the image below shows &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im/app/#/room/%23neuroscience-central-lobby:matrix.org"&gt;Neuroscience-central/Lobby&lt;/a&gt; room  that I've set up on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;. But, I've also gone ahead and connected this room to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitter.im/neuroscience-central/Lobby"&gt;Neuroscience-central/Lobby room on Gitter&lt;/a&gt;, and to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=#neuroscience-central-lobby"&gt;#neuroscience-central-lobby channel on IRC&lt;/a&gt;. So, everyone on any of these platforms can communicate with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170628-riot-gitter.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Neuroscience-Central/Lobby on Riot integrated with the same room on Gitter." class="text-center img-responsive pagination-centered" src="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170628-riot-gitter.png" style="width: 70%;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting up the integrations is rather easy too. One needs to go to the integrations tab and set them up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170628-riot-integrations.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Integrations on Riot" class="text-center img-responsive pagination-centered" src="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170628-riot-integrations.png" style="width: 70%;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im/desktop.html"&gt;desktop clients&lt;/a&gt; available for &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; too. (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://copr.fedorainfracloud.org/coprs/taw/Riot/"&gt;Here's a COPR for Fedora&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://opensource.com/article/17/5/introducing-riot-IRC"&gt;Here's a great post on opensource.com&lt;/a&gt; discussing &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you're an admin looking to set up a new chat channel - consider setting up on different platforms and integrating them with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; - it'll make things a lot easier for your users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Community"></category><category term="Computational neuroscience"></category><category term="Fedora"></category><category term="FlatPak"></category><category term="Free software"></category><category term="Gitter"></category><category term="Linux"></category><category term="Planet"></category></entry><entry><title>A channel for neuroscientists on Gitter</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2017/06/26/a-channel-for-neuroscientists-on-gitter.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-06-26T10:30:01+01:00</published><updated>2017-06-26T10:30:01+01:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2017-06-26:/2017/06/26/a-channel-for-neuroscientists-on-gitter.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;I've come across a few mailing lists for neuroscientists, but I couldn't find a chat channel. While mailing lists suit certain purposes, open source communities tend to use a combination of mailing lists and chat channels - each platform serves different purposes. TLDR: here's a new chat channel on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gitterHQ"&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitter.im/neuroscience-central/Lobby"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for everything neuroscience related. It is also accessible using the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=#neuroscience-central-lobby"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im/app/#/room/#neuroscience-central-lobby:matrix.org"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As opposed to the free software community, where I've been around long enough to know what's where, I'm still relatively new to the neuroscience community. Over the two years that I've been doing my PhD, I've found a few neuroscience related mailing lists, but not any chat channels. Various teams tend to use &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slack.com/"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; or another platform for internal communications, but nothing seems to be set up for the community in general - an open for all channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mailing lists are extremely useful, but by design they are suited to particular types of tasks. They are very well suited for longer discussions, and general queries that are not time sensitive, for example. On the other hand, they do not work well for urgent queries, and of course, sometimes sending e-mails back and forth is quite an overhead for simpler tasks or collaborative development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most open source communities have both mailing lists and chat channels. I figured it'd be nice to have one for the neuroscience community too. There's the question of what platform was best suited, of course. We use &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slack.com/"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; for our internal communication, but &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slack.com/"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; only works well for small teams. It isn't designed for larger communities. The &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt; is ideal for larger communities, but on the flip side, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt; is not very user friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third option, and the popular alternative to IRC and Slack, is &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gitterHQ"&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt; - it's been recently &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://about.gitlab.com/2017/03/15/gitter-acquisition/"&gt;acquired by GitLab&lt;/a&gt; and will be completely open sourced soon. It's completely free to use unlike &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://slack.com/"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; where one needs to pay more as the number of group members increases, and is designed for large communities that number in the thousands. One can login using either Github or Twitter - so that's quite convenient too. There's even an &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://irc.gitter.im/"&gt;IRC gateway&lt;/a&gt; for more technical users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here's the channel then - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitter.im/neuroscience-central/Lobby"&gt;https://gitter.im/neuroscience-central/Lobby&lt;/a&gt;. I hope it'll be useful, and if it doesn't, well no harm done :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update (12 July 2017):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enable people to communicate over various platforms, I've also set the channel up with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;. This enables people using &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/gitterHQ"&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ankursinha.in/2017/07/12/bringing-together-gitter-irc-and-slack-channels-in-one-place-on-riot.html"&gt;communicate with each other in one place using whatever platform they prefer&lt;/a&gt;. So, we also have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://webchat.freenode.net/?channels=#neuroscience-central-lobby"&gt;#neuroscience-central-lobby&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_Relay_Chat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im/app/#/room/#neuroscience-central-lobby:matrix.org"&gt;neuroscience-central/Lobby&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://riot.im"&gt;Riot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content><category term="Community"></category><category term="Computational neuroscience"></category><category term="Gitter"></category><category term="Planet"></category></entry><entry><title>Using Wallabag to manage your online reading list</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2017/02/28/using-wallabag-to-manage-your-online-reading-list.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-28T20:52:40+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-28T20:52:40+00:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2017-02-28:/2017/02/28/using-wallabag-to-manage-your-online-reading-list.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;I've recently begun using &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://wallabag.org/en"&gt;Wallabag&lt;/a&gt; to manage my reading list. It is released under the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tldrlegal.com/license/mit-license"&gt;MIT license&lt;/a&gt;, so it's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.en.html"&gt;Free software&lt;/a&gt; too!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Edit (28 February 2017): Earlier today, it was &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2017/02/27/mozilla-acquires-pocket/"&gt;announced that Mozilla had acquired Pocket&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bugzil.la/1343006"&gt;plans to gradually release the Pocket source code under Open Source licenses&lt;/a&gt;.  I guess &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://wallabag.org/en"&gt;Wallabag&lt;/a&gt; will remain as a self hosted solution, but given an improved integration of Pocket with Firefox, I may move back to it in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always have quite a bit on my pending list to read - academic papers, blogs, planets, and the sort. Usually, when I go through the planets, such as the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://fedoraplanet.org/"&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://planet.gnome.org/"&gt;GNOME&lt;/a&gt; or the two neuroscience planets I use - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscience/"&gt;neuroscience&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://sanjayankur31.github.io/planet-neuroscientists/"&gt;neuroscientists&lt;/a&gt;, I don't have the time to read all the articles right then. I used to either bookmark links, or note them down somewhere to read later. One day, though, I ran into &lt;a class="reference external" href="getpocket.com/"&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt;, which lets you save the article to read later and makes it available to you on multiple devices. It's extremely convenient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the one issue with &lt;a class="reference external" href="getpocket.com/"&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; is that it isn't &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.en.html"&gt;Free software&lt;/a&gt;. So, like I do, I went looking for an alternative. After a few hours, I ran into &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://wallabag.org/en"&gt;Wallabag&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/wallabag/wallabag"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. It's written in PHP, and is licensed under the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://tldrlegal.com/license/mit-license"&gt;MIT license&lt;/a&gt;. It's quite easy to deploy, and there's a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitter.im/wallabag/wallabag"&gt;Gitter channel&lt;/a&gt; where you can get some help too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You either enter the URL in the Wallabag page manually, or you can use the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://addons.mozilla.org/firefox/addon/wallabagger/"&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/wallabagger/gbmgphmejlcoihgedabhgjdkcahacjlj"&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://addons.opera.com/en/extensions/details/wallabagger/?display=en"&gt;Opera&lt;/a&gt; addon - it let's you right click a page or a link and &amp;quot;Wallabag.it!&amp;quot;. There's also a bookmarklet, which you can use with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/5digits/dactyl"&gt;Pentadactyl&lt;/a&gt;, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code bash literal-block"&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Add to ~/.pentadactylrc
&lt;/span&gt;command! wallabagit -description &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Add to wallabag&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; open javascript:&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;var%20url&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;location.href&lt;span class="o"&gt;||&lt;/span&gt;url&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;var%20wllbg&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;window.open&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'https://app.wallabag.it/bookmarklet?url='&lt;/span&gt;%20+%20encodeURI&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;url&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class="s1"&gt;'_blank'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;})()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wallabag fetches the text of the page and stores it for you so that you can read it later. You can even organise your saved pages with tags and the sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170220-wallabag.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Screenshot showing the Wallabag main page" class="img-responsive align-center" src="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170220-wallabag.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a page that I'm trying to read later, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170220-wallabag-2.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Screenshot showing an article in Wallabag" class="img-responsive align-center" src="http://ankursinha.in/images/20170220-wallabag-2.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played with a deployment, but decided not to deploy and maintain an instance myself. Instead, I signed up for the instance Wallabag have here - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.wallabag.it/en"&gt;Wallabag.it&lt;/a&gt;. It's quite cheap - they have an offer going too at the moment - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://wallabag.org/en/news/wallabagit"&gt;only 9€ for an entire year&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wallabag uses a the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://fivefilters.org/content-only/"&gt;FiveFilters Full Text RSS tool&lt;/a&gt; to extract the text and other data from web pages. Some websites require special instructions to tell the tool what information needs to be extracted - this tends to happen with a few academic websites. There's a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/fivefilters/ftr-site-config"&gt;repository of such config files here&lt;/a&gt;. So, if you do run into a website that isn't rendering properly, you can &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://doc.wallabag.org/en/master/user/errors_during_fetching.html"&gt;troubleshoot the issue and submit a config file too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you decide to deploy an instance yourself, or use &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.wallabag.it/en"&gt;Wallabag.it&lt;/a&gt;, I think it's a really useful tool to have. Of course, don't forget to install the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=fr.gaulupeau.apps.InThePoche&amp;amp;hl=en"&gt;app on your phone&lt;/a&gt; too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Fedora"></category><category term="Wallabag"></category><category term="Planet"></category><category term="Reading"></category></entry></feed>