<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>ankursinha.in/blog - Rant</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ankursinha.in/feeds/tags/rant.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ankursinha.in/</id><updated>2012-04-25T11:30:00+01:00</updated><subtitle>neuroscience/fedora/musings</subtitle><entry><title>A bad day with free-media in India</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2012/04/25/one-of-the-worse-days-with-free-media-in-india.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-04-25T11:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2012-04-25T11:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2012-04-25:/2012/04/25/one-of-the-worse-days-with-free-media-in-india.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The quotes will say it all:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Mr.ankur,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will I ever recieve this media?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My reply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Mr abc,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I agree that it's taking longer than usual to get media to
you, I do not appreciate you pretending as if you have the right to
any media …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The quotes will say it all:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Mr.ankur,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will I ever recieve this media?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regards,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My reply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Mr abc,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I agree that it's taking longer than usual to get media to
you, I do not appreciate you pretending as if you have the right to
any media that free-media sends out. If you were ready to take some,
ANY trouble whatsoever, you could have gone ahead and collected
media from an Ambassador right away! Instead, you prefer to sit at
home and get media delivered to you, FREE of cost, without putting
in any effort other than moving your fingers on a key board: how
convenient. You are in Bangalore, as per my earlier comment, we have
numerous ambassadors in Koramangla. Even if you are new to
Bangalore, finding out what bus to take to reach Koramangala on a
weekend is really not a lot to ask. It's been a month, right? Still
new to Bangalore?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two categories of people who request media from us. One,
who understand that we volunteers are taking out time from our busy
lives, and spending our money to get media across to you. Such
people are very patient and profusely grateful: One of them even
sent me a money order with the postal and media charge. It was the
least he could do for getting media sitting at home, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other category, is one that thinks we are a government service
running by tax payers money. They think they have the right to have
media delivered at their door step, without moving an inch, without
paying a paisa. We are not, make no mistake. We are doing this out
of goodwill, and our love for Fedora. We are not doing it to feed
ingrates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sorry. I'm not going to send out media to you. Please file a
fresh ticket next month and wait for someone to accept it, or
purchase from one of the many online vendors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No further emails from you will be entertained, Sir. The ticket is
closed, so is the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ankur&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This person filed a ticket last month. I ran out of x86_64 media so I
replied saying I'll send him media with the March batch. I haven't
gotten down to sending it out yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is in Bangalore, where almost 5 of us Ambassadors are. He has an
Ambassador who is two bus rides away! &amp;quot;But why take the trouble? It
should come at my doorstep, I have the right!&amp;quot; What right Sir?! I really
fail to understand this! WHAT right!?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A majority of requesters are not even polite enough to inform us that
the media was deliverd. A minority emails, thanking us. This person is a
whole new level. One that I could not ignore.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="Fedora"></category><category term="Rant"></category></entry><entry><title>Text messaging woes</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2010/11/28/text-messaging-woes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-11-28T14:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-11-28T14:40:00+00:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2010-11-28:/2010/11/28/text-messaging-woes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes, it's a rant.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;rant&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I came across this article on text-messaging, and how this
simple method of communication was taking over the world with more and
more users turning to their thumbs for communication. (I can't recall
where I came across the article sadly).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, text-messaging might be …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes, it's a rant.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;rant&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I came across this article on text-messaging, and how this
simple method of communication was taking over the world with more and
more users turning to their thumbs for communication. (I can't recall
where I came across the article sadly).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, text-messaging might be taking over the world in interactive
entertainment, but in my very honest opinion, it's still a crappy way of
actually communicating with one another. Broadly speaking, its a
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Connectionless_protocol"&gt;connection less protocol&lt;/a&gt;. It lacks sequencing AND delivery is not
guaranteed, neither is a time frame for delivery.(Added bonus: Operators
make most of it when they surprise us by charging messages on random
holidays without prior notice). It's really really REALLY irritating
when messages land up in random order, or do not land up at all, or land
up after half an hour during a conversation. You can't make out head to
tail of what just happened! Let's not ignore misinterpretation of
messages. It's highly unlikely that the sender and receiver read the
message in the same way, the tones vary, the expression has to be
assumed by the individual. Usually lands the two of you in the gutter. I
can't really miss out on mentioning the weird messages you get when
people don't understand that CAPITALS IMPLY SHOUTING. Messages from
random acquaintances when they need you to run an errand for them are
most special to me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm old school,. I prefer calling instead of texting (with rates in
India, calling isn't expensive). Socially speaking, texting lets you
stay in touch with a lot of people. So many people actually, that you
really lose track of whose actually worth keeping in touch with, and
whose an ass. Do me a favour, make a one minute call and tell the
concerned person what you need to? Restrict messages to mass
announcements which don't need ACKs, or for voting on your favouring TV
show. Would do the world a lot of good. Actually saves time and work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel better now..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;/rant&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Other"></category><category term="Rant"></category></entry></feed>