<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>ankursinha.in/blog - RPMFusion</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ankursinha.in/feeds/tags/rpmfusion.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ankursinha.in/</id><updated>2015-09-25T14:57:53+01:00</updated><entry><title>Hello from Fedora 23!</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2015/09/25/hello-from-fedora-23.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-25T14:57:53+01:00</published><updated>2015-09-25T14:57:53+01:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2015-09-25:/2015/09/25/hello-from-fedora-23.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Upgraded to Fedora 23 and it works like a charm!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;center&gt;&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://ankursinha.in/images/Fedora23.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Fedora 23" src="http://ankursinha.in/images/Fedora23.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello from Fedora 23!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just upgraded not one, not two, not three, but &lt;strong&gt;four&lt;/strong&gt; of my Fedora systems using the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/DNF_system_upgrade"&gt;dnf system-upgrade plugin&lt;/a&gt; and it worked like a charm in each case. Three were workstation installations while the last was a server installation, and I'm happy to report that after the upgrade, they're all alive and healthy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm using Gnome on my Fedora system, so I now have the new Gnome 3.18 release. I haven't had any crashes yet - all the applications that I use frequently - Gnome Terminal, Evolution, Firefox, Nautilus, Revelation, Gnome Software, and a bunch of others seem to work just right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is going to be another marvellous Fedora release! Hurray!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Fedora"></category><category term="GNOME"></category><category term="Linux"></category><category term="RPMFusion"></category></entry><entry><title>Appstream data for RPMFusion - now available!</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2015/05/28/appstream-data-for-rpmfusion-now-available.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-28T21:56:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-05-28T21:56:00+01:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2015-05-28:/2015/05/28/appstream-data-for-rpmfusion-now-available.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;Appstream data for RPMFusion repositories for Fedora 22 packages are now available as easy to install RPM packages.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ankursinha.in/2015/05/25/appdata-for-rpmfusion.html"&gt;I've been working on generating appstream data for RPMFusion packages recently&lt;/a&gt;. At the moment, since only Fedora packages provide appstream data, only they can be installed using Gnome software - for RPMFusion packages, a user must use another package manager - DNF and so on. Considering that a lot of the packages in RPMFusion are media player front-ends and things, it'd make it a lot easier for users if these were also listed in Gnome software. I spent a number of hours today writing appstream data files for the RPMFusion packages - both in the free and non free repositories. I believe I've written appstream data files for all packages that could be listed in Gnome software now. (They're hosted here in the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/sanjayankur31/rpmfusion-appdata"&gt;Github repository I set up for this purpose&lt;/a&gt;). I had already generated initial RPM packages for the free and non free repositories and submitted review tickets to RPMFusion. They're still unassigned, so if you are a package maintainer with a few free cycles, please consider reviewing them. They are really simple reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bugzilla.rpmfusion.org/show_bug.cgi?id=3658"&gt;Package review: rpmfusion-nonfree-appstream-data - Appstream metadata for the RPMFusion nonfree repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bugzilla.rpmfusion.org/show_bug.cgi?id=3657"&gt;Package review: rpmfusion-free-appstream-data - Appstream metadata for the RPMFusion free repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've now updated the packages submitted for review to use meta data from the new appstream information I wrote. A majority of the RPMFusion GUI packages are now included. You can install the RPMs from here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ankursinha.in/files/misc/rpmfusion/rpmfusion-free-appstream-data-22-4.fc22.noarch.rpm"&gt;rpmfusion-free-appstream-data-22-4.fc22.noarch.rpm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ankursinha.in/files/misc/rpmfusion/rpmfusion-nonfree-appstream-data-22-4.fc22.noarch.rpm"&gt;rpmfusion-nonfree-appstream-data-22-4.fc22.noarch.rpm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to use the terminal, you can run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo dnf install http://ankursinha.in/files/misc/rpmfusion/rpmfusion-free-appstream-data-22-4.fc22.noarch.rpm http://ankursinha.in/files/misc/rpmfusion/rpmfusion-nonfree-appstream-data-22-4.fc22.noarch.rpm
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'll need to kill and restart Gnome software to get it to load the new appstream data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, for example, you can now install &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mixxx.org/"&gt;Mixxx&lt;/a&gt; from RPMFusion using Gnome software!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://ankursinha.in/images/20150528-mixx-gs.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Screenshot showing Mixxx in Gnome software" class="align-center" src="http://ankursinha.in/images/20150528-mixx-gs.png" style="width: 500px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or, you can pick which of the many Xine front ends that are available in RPMFusion you'd like to install:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://ankursinha.in/images/20150528-xine-search-gs.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Screenshot showing multiple Xine front ends available in RPMFusion in Gnome software." class="align-center" src="http://ankursinha.in/images/20150528-xine-search-gs.png" style="width: 500px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screen-shots are currently hosted on my fedora people space, but once the packages are added to RPMFusion, we'll probably move them there too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that I've written about &lt;strong&gt;a hundred&lt;/strong&gt; appdata files at a stretch, so there probably will be a few typos, formatting errors, and so on in them. If you do run into any, please open a pull request at the Github repository and help improve them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since RPMFusion's package set is much smaller than Fedora's, and there aren't too many updates and things in general, I don't think the appstream data will need to be regenerated frequently - but I will update them once a fortnight, just in case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the amazing &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://fedoramagazine.org/fedora-22-alpha-released/"&gt;Fedora 22 release&lt;/a&gt;. Cheerio!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Fedora"></category><category term="RPMFusion"></category></entry></feed>