<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>ankursinha.in/blog - Social</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ankursinha.in/feeds/tags/social.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ankursinha.in/</id><updated>2017-03-04T17:35:32+00:00</updated><entry><title>Fedora Free Media programme group refresh</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2017/03/04/fedora-free-media-programme-group-refresh.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-04T17:35:32+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-04T17:35:32+00:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2017-03-04:/2017/03/04/fedora-free-media-programme-group-refresh.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;As part of the migration of the Fedora &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/FreeMedia"&gt;Free Media&lt;/a&gt; group, we're refreshing the FAS group membership!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://communityblog.fedoraproject.org/fedorahosted-sunset-2017-02-28/"&gt;Fedorahosted closed down at the end of last month&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/FreeMedia"&gt;Free Media&lt;/a&gt; has quite a few components and we haven't been able to migrate the pipeline to Pagure completely yet. In fact, we've temporarily closed &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/FreeMedia"&gt;Free Media&lt;/a&gt; down for the moment - the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://fedoraproject.org/freemedia/FreeMedia-form.html"&gt;form&lt;/a&gt; says so too. Since we're re-doing the complete process and the infrastructure, we also decided to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pagure.io/Free-Media/Housekeeping/issue/7"&gt;refresh the membership list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd e-mailed the mailing list and all members of the FAS informing them of this already. I've now gone ahead and cleared up the FAS group and the mailing list. In the new Pagure based workflow, this is the process to join the team:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pagure.io/Free-Media/Housekeeping/new_issue"&gt;File a ticket&lt;/a&gt; at the Housekeeping Pagure instance with [membership-request] in the title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the ticket, please mention:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your FAS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A link to your Fedora User wiki page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The e-mail address you'd like to subscribe to the mailing list with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An admin will accept the ticket, verify the information, and add you to the FAS group, Pagure group, and the mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of work still to do before we can complete the migration and re-enable the Free Media programme. If you'd like to help out, please take a look at the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pagure.io/Free-Media/Housekeeping/issues"&gt;open issues on the Housekeeping Pagure instance&lt;/a&gt;, or of course, get in touch with me. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Community"></category><category term="Fedora"></category><category term="Social"></category><category term="Subscriptions"></category></entry><entry><title>On jargon</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2016/10/17/on-jargon.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-17T08:26:30+01:00</published><updated>2016-10-17T08:26:30+01:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2016-10-17:/2016/10/17/on-jargon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;When we speak of jargon, it is usually because we heard something we couldn't make sense of. We focus on how it adversely affects the listener. The truth is, it also affects the speaker if the speaker does indeed intend to get the point across. In this post I discuss how it affects my work and me and I try to document what I can do to improve my communications to make it easier for my listeners and me to understand each other correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jargon is more often than not looked at unfavourably. Jargon is just the &amp;quot;language of a trade&amp;quot; and so, by itself, I don't see why I should denounce it. Rather, to me, it is the usage of jargon that is the issue. If you think of a workplace where people are aware of the context and meaning of certain jargon, I see no reason why it isn't appropriate usage. In fact, in such scenarios, jargon makes conversation efficient since the parties must not needlessly simplify their communications. So, when I go over to my lab mate's desk and say &amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;well, the STDP rule doesn't seem to result in an AI state&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;, he knows exactly what I mean. I'd find it quite difficult to rephrase that sentence to make it any simpler. The same applies for most professions if not all of them. Whether it's farming or mechanics; IT or medicine; cooking or sewing; designing or the media; they will all have some specialised terminology. It is just normal evolution of language in the same way that &amp;quot;selfie&amp;quot; is now a word. Jargon is simply a set of words that encapsulate concepts that are frequently used in a context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why are we up in arms about jargon, then? Why is everyone continuously talking about how we need to cut it out? Quite simply, because when jargon is used in the wrong scenario, it hampers transfer of information. If work related terminology is used in a social setting where other listeners are not privy to it, for example, the conversation does not serve to pass on any material. Furthermore, it usually has the effect of making the audience feel out of place. It is quite similar to speaking to a single member of a group in a language that the others do not comprehend. It is considered impolite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To take it a step further, jargon seems to be used frequently with the malintent to obfuscate - especially in sales and marketing. The idea seems to be to coin and use fancy wording to trick consumers into buying products. The billboards and slogans that we see on a daily basis while not untrue, are not always created with aim to elucidate facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another use of jargon is straightforward snobbery. It makes the snob feel like part of an exclusive club. There isn't much to say about this other than that one should simply not engage with such individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scenarios where the use of jargon is unintentional are more complex to deal with. Most research falls in this category. Consider people like me who spend a majority of their time in an environment that requires the use of an uncommon vocabulary. So, I read research papers that contain specific words, I write papers using these same words, the discussions I partake in utilise these too - this jargon is quite unavoidable to a large extent in work life. I'm only 2 years into my Ph.D. and I find it hard to speak about the same subject matter without employing the same dialect already. While this does not affect my daily activities as they are limited to colleagues who are well versed in our diction, it greatly limits my ability to spread the science I work in to a wider audience. This, in contrast, does effect me, and you too. If we're not working similar areas, we have very little understanding of each other's work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I can't speak for types of work, this, in general, is an issue in research and academia - the lack of ability in us researchers to disseminate our work to people in other streams, especially non research careers, is an accepted weakness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computational neuroscience, for example, is extremely multidisciplinary. At my lab alone, we have biologists, physicist, mathematicians, and us computer scientists, all working under the same roof on similar research questions. The dialect each of us speak is different. Yet, we read and publish in the same channels. When I read a paper that is heavy on biological detail, I find it much harder because the text utilises biological terminology that I'm not well aware of. In our case, though, there's only the one solution of learning what we need to know. It is how we manage to collaborate across disciplines, and it takes work - the difference in jargon ever so slightly increasing the required exertions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extend this scenario to someone who isn't working in computational neuroscience at all. Of course, it'll be even harder for them to understand the same text. Given how important research is for all life in general, it is imperative that people who do not conduct research be made aware of progress that is continuously made. If you don't understand why research is important, let me point out to you that &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; manufactured product you use in your home is the end result of some research somewhere. Take a moment to wonder how it all came about - it isn't magic; it is years of hard work and failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To insure the future of research, it is important that young students are exposed to it at an early age. It is the simplest way of arousing enough interest in them to guarantee that research receives a constant stream of capable bearers to build on past innovations. It really doesn't matter what they take up - contributions to each field count.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also helpful for consumers to have some idea of how things are manufactured and the amount of work that goes into it. It helps them pick between brands and decide what price they should pay for a product. A general awareness helps build immunity to the different tricks in use today that gently nudge consumers into buying products - creating demand for a product that wasn't required some time before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A last but important note is that most research makes use of public funds that are obtained via government grants. If the tax payer is funding some research, the tax payer should know how the money is being utilised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yes, making research information easily accessible to everyone is of great value. This is where jargon stands out as quite a bottle neck. Individuals that are not aware of the context, or those that do not have the required background knowledge cannot be expected to read research papers to understand the state of knowledge. Rather, academics have to work towards simplifying the data to an extent that it can be consumed by individuals from all walks of life. This isn't easy, and simplification usually goes hand in hand with omission of lesser important details but it is certainly possible to synthesise an overall picture of a concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I've written isn't new by any standards. The problem is well known, and communities are working towards making knowledge more understandable. If you watch the stuff the BBC puts up, for example, you'll see a lot of work by individuals like &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brian_Cox_(physicist)"&gt;Professor Brian Cox&lt;/a&gt; that is aimed at explaining complex physical phenomena in simpler terms. A start has certainly been made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point of this post was to give myself some time to think about the issue. After writing about a thousand words on the subject, I have a better understanding of it myself. I also have a better handle on what I should do to do my bit. It simply takes practice and some feedback. That's all it is. So, as I blog frequently about my Fedora related activities, I am going to make more of an attempt to write about my research too. A target is always helpful. Since it takes some effort at the moment, I'm going to set myself a target of one research related post every two to three weeks to begin with. Today being the 16th of October, I'll publish the first one before the 7th of November. Let's see how that goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Computational neuroscience"></category><category term="Fedora"></category><category term="Social"></category></entry><entry><title>Learning to swim as an adult: Part I - Learning to not drown</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2015/10/25/learning-to-swim-as-an-adult-part-i-learning-to-not-drown.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-25T18:04:10+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-25T18:04:10+00:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2015-10-25:/2015/10/25/learning-to-swim-as-an-adult-part-i-learning-to-not-drown.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;I'm finally learning to swim!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;center&gt;&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Fireman_swimming_by_mimooh.svg"&gt;&lt;img alt="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Fireman_swimming_by_mimooh.svg that is under the `CC by SA 3.0 unported license &amp;lt;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en&amp;gt;`__." src="http://ankursinha.in/images/20151025-learning-to-swim-as-an-adult-i-learning-to-not-drown.png" style="height: 200.0px;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Fireman_swimming_by_mimooh.svg"&gt;From wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; and under the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en"&gt;CC by SA 3.0 unported license&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;p&gt;The facts to begin with. I'll turn 30 in a few years. I can't swim. Well, I couldn't even float till a fortnight ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="why"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me not knowing to swim has often come as quite a shock to a lot of the people that I've met in my life. More lately so since I moved out of a developing India to developed Australia and now England. It's quite common in India for someone to not know to swim. Quite a few people that live in land-locked areas, and a majority of India is land-locked, don't have access to swimming pools. The ones that do are generally too busy working or studying to ensure that they'll be employable when the time comes. Since a lot of parents don't swim themselves, they are unable to pass on the skill to their kids either. It's just a very different scenario to the one in developed countries where it's highly probable that even smaller towns will have swimming pools and the other infrastructure that goes with it. Of course, one can always say that these are all just excuses, but they're really not. You need to live the scenario to understand it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I did have a chance to learn to swim at boarding school. We had a small pool for kids that couldn't swim, and sometimes we even had an instructor that would try to teach us to swim. Here are my personal excuses for not making the most of this opportunity, and while none of them sound convincing enough, you need to remember that I was a stupid kid at this time - almost as stupid as I am today, maybe a little less even. Firstly, it was 30 of us crammed into a pool at a time, so it wasn't really the best environment to learn with kids barging into each other and all that sort of thing. Then, secondly, swimming season happened to fall during the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monsoon_of_South_Asia"&gt;Monsoons&lt;/a&gt;. To make this worse, so did Football season (we had the year divided into Cricket, Football and Hockey seasons and since neither Cricket nor Hockey can be played in the rain, it had to be Football during the rains). In the lower Himalayas, during the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monsoon_of_South_Asia"&gt;Monsoons&lt;/a&gt;, it generally rains weeks on end. Everything is wet and cold - it used to be so depressing that when the sun did finally come out, it prompted the head master to sometimes give us a &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;Sunshine Holiday&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; (&lt;em&gt;This most agreeable event was subtly announced by getting the chapel choir to sing &amp;quot;All things bright and beautiful&amp;quot; at the daily assembly, after which a teacher or another would come up and formally announce it - to lots of cheers and excitement, of course. I don't think the students were ever happier!&lt;/em&gt;). This already made the idea of spending time &lt;strong&gt;unclothed&lt;/strong&gt; in an &lt;strong&gt;outdoor unheated pool in the rain&lt;/strong&gt; quite unappealing. Add to that the thrill of playing Football with mates, and a land loving kid like me almost never gave swimming a thought. I did go down to the pool once or twice to be perfectly honest, but I didn't get too far. I could hold on to the side wall and paddle, but then everyone can do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing about not knowing how to swim, though, is that the older you get, the smaller the window of opportunity to learn gets. At school, there's the fact that your classmates will probably have a massive laugh at your expense when they see you flapping around in the water like a maniac - at boarding school, where you spend majority of your life with your classmates, &lt;em&gt;it's generally a good idea to keep embarrassing moments to a minimum&lt;/em&gt;. Unlike regular schools, you don't get to escape to mummy at the end of the day. Whatever it is, you face it there and then, possibly for days and nights afterwords. I don't mean this as a disadvantage of boarding schools at all, though. On the contrary, I prefer boarding schools any day - &lt;em&gt;you learn how to face everything that life can throw at you on your own, and that is a very very important skill to know - more important than swimming even&lt;/em&gt;. As you get older, other things come up too. For example, the Football you play gets more involved as it gets more structured and serious, since you begin to understand tactics and formations and all that sort of thing (When we were little, Football was more like a Brownian motion dictated by a Football - 20 kids kicking and chasing the ball around the park until somehow it ended up in the back of the net after beating a mostly bored and uninterested goalie). Your academics get harder and you need to spend a lot more time on your coursework. The number of co-curricular activities that you are expected to participate in increase - debates, elocutions, drama, clubs and societies, the choir even. Of course, then there's puberty that clobbers you mercilessly in the nuts with a spade and all sorts of relationshipy things begin to demand time - funnily enough, even if you aren't in a relationship. &lt;strong&gt;TLDR - lot busier, swimming not really that high up on the priority list.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="why-now"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow, learning how to swim has always been on my bucket list for a variety of reasons. Even though neither of my parents can swim themselves, they've always reminded me that it was something I needed to learn for myself. It was something they said they couldn't help me with, that it was my responsibility. I am also aware that swimming can be a most relaxing experience, and luckily, swimming is an exercise that covers all muscle groups too. Being in Europe also implies that a lot of my holidays nowadays are to sunlit beaches, and while I do venture into the water, I'd like to swim in it too. I missed out on this while I was in Sydney, but once I learn I do intend to head back down under and enjoy myself at the many beaches there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I received an e-mail that said that the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.activestudents.co.uk/"&gt;active students initiative&lt;/a&gt; were hosting a six week &amp;quot;swimming for dummies&amp;quot; course at very nominal prices - 25£ only - I really didn't have an excuse. I signed up right away, and even though the sessions began the next day which gave me very little time to prepare myself mentally, I did go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-first-class"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The first class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I was nervous. I got there about half an hour earlier than required and quietly sat in a corner preparing myself. I've never been scared of water - as long as I have at least a foot on the floor, that is. I've just never been confident enough to get both my feet off the pool's floor. &lt;em&gt;With six weeks to change that, I needed to convince myself that if I did let myself go in the water, I wouldn't encounter an excruciating death where water would fill my lungs until I'd maybe see my dead grandmother's ghost or something else that I didn't care for at all and then asphyxiate painfully to inadvertently but successfully prove the non existence of the afterlife to my non-existent self&lt;/em&gt;. To a swimmer, this almost sounds ridiculous - once you know how to float, you pretty much cannot drown - it becomes a sort of reflex. BUT, to someone who has never floated before, it really is a big deal. I could feel the adrenaline and I did the best to calm myself down. Even though there's oodles of logic out there that should easily convince me that I'd float, somehow, the trepidation wouldn't go away. The difficult thing about floating, which I now understand, is that you need to just let go - literally. So, in order to have some control over what you do in the water, you must first relinquish all control. I tried the usual tactics. I explained the physics of it to myself over and over. I've studied liquids and flotation in great detail at school - reminding myself of the concepts of buoyancy and displacement helped a bit. The next was reminding myself that I was an intelligent adult that was in the middle of his Ph.D. in neuroscience; one that loved Maths and found it fun even; one that did pretty well at most physical activities whether it was sprinting or Football; one that managed to pack up his life in India and move not once, but twice, to completely new continents. If the rest of the world, a majority of which seem to have a rather incomprehensible phobia of something as simple as Maths could figure out how to swim, surely I ruddy could too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the time to convert all this talk into action had come. I learned that there are 7 of us in the group - which is good. A smaller group means that the instructor can pay more attention to each of us individually. None of us could swim at all when we began, which was even better. We are all also in the same age group which was a relief to find out - all of us later confessed to being a bit worried that we'd be in class with little kids, which would be a bit embarrassing somehow. Being in the same boat as a few others calmed all our nerves down a bit, I'd think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing we were supposed to do was to try and float with the help of a long cylindrical floatation tube thing (I have no idea what it's called). The idea was to just let yourself go while holding the tube under your arms. The instructor kept telling us that we could trust him when he said the float would keep us from drowning. It took me a few minutes to try it out even. I kept standing on one leg trying to command myself to lift it off the floor. I tried a bit and went down, obviously, since you have to go down a bit to displace some water before you float (now I understand it!). Nope, foot back on the floor it is. A few more minutes and I finally convinced myself to trust a yellow coloured floating tube with my life. I basically relaxed and lay face down in the water - a bit of panic set in initially and I had this strong urge to cancel the attempt and put my foot down again. Somehow, and I really haven't a clue how, I kept leaning in until, almost like a miracle, I felt the water holding me up! Was I happy!! This was my Eureka moment - I was almost naked too! I tried it a few times to see if I'd gotten it right and in my excitement managed to gulp down a bit of the pool water - I'd forgotten the importance of &amp;quot;keep your mouth closed in the water&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sessions are each only 30 minutes long. For the rest of the first session, I tried to propel myself forward. Somehow, I kept turning to the right. Clearly lots of work to do there. I was also told that I need to work on my body shape a bit. I was trying to keep my head out of the water, which meant my back arched backwards. Not only does this make floating more difficult, it also gives you a back ache as I found out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I came out of the water really pleased with my progress. For a change, I was looking forward to the next session instead of dreading it. Funny how one experience can change your perspective about something so much!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-second-class"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The second class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second session was yesterday. Most of the group had returned. After the relative success of the first session, we'd have been stupid not to. It took me a few minutes to float again - even though I'd done it last week, doing it again was just a little scary (&amp;quot;I hope I haven't forgotten!&amp;quot;). Once I'd done that, the next was to try and float with my head inside the water - to improve on my body shape which would improve my technique and also spare me the back pain. Surprisingly, this didn't take much effort. After a bit, I was slowly moving forward with my head submerged - this was the first time I'd kept my eyes open under water long enough to see the pool floor move away backwards beneath me. This served as positive reinforcement and I was internally pleased with myself. I wanted to smile, but this time I was aware enough not to grin with my mouth open like I'd done last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instructor came over and gave me some pointers after a bit. Instead of kicking from the hip, I was kicking from the knee, for instance. Using the knees doesn't propel you as much as kicking from the hips would. The instructor said they call the correct technique &amp;quot;ballerina legs&amp;quot;. I worked on this finer side of myself for a bit - trying to propel myself forward while pointing my toes out and keeping my knees very straight - imagining myself to be delicate ballerina (not really!). I did get a lot further than I before. Then came the &lt;strong&gt;upgrade&lt;/strong&gt; - the instructor said I'd done enough to switch the big tube thing for two small rectangular floats which provided less support. Yay! I happily remarked that we'd probably be better off without knowing that detail on the less support. Again though, great timely positive reinforcement. I tried to do a bit without pausing - exhaling and inhaling while I propelled forward. I think I managed to do half a length before I gulped down some water(&lt;em&gt;again!&lt;/em&gt;) and had to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the instructor called time, we were all a bit disappointed. Since we'd been improving, we really wanted to spend more time in the water and practice our technique. Still, I think each one of us is a lot more confident in the water now, and for only two week's work, it's pretty great. Next week, we're going to learn how to use our arms - sort of getting started with the free style. As we walked back to the showers, we saw this little girl swim underwater and one of the guys jokingly went, &amp;quot;Look at her! The little show off!&amp;quot; - everyone broke into a laugh. Clearly, we'd begun enjoying ourselves!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion-it-s-all-in-the-head"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion - it's all in the head&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It really is. The way I approached it, it's a mental battle with oneself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have different goals in life. Mine, quite simply, is to keep improving - in whatever aspect I can, whether it's my research or my physical fitness. Sometimes you just need to wait for the right time, and the right chance. Of course, sometimes you'll take the chance but mess it up royally. I just messed up something amazing last night, and I've been kicking myself since and I expect to keep kicking myself for the next few months too. Hopefully, though, when I get another chance, and I will, I'll know better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning to swim was a big item on the bucket list, and now that I've initiated, I'm going to keep working on it until I'm a fairly strong swimmer. I have no intention to compete and all that, but if I can learn the strokes well enough to add a weekly swim session to my fitness regime, I think that'd be a pretty good result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To those who still can't swim, I hope this short tale will serve as encouragement and convince you to give it a good old fashioned try. All you pretty much need to do is float &lt;strong&gt;once&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I conclude, I must express my gratitude to our instructor, George, without whom none of us would've learned. He really knows what he's doing, and he knows how to get people to trust him enough to do what he asks. He also makes us feel safe in the water, which is paramount in the first few sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Social"></category><category term="Sports"></category><category term="Fedora"></category></entry><entry><title>Pelican and github pages - a quickstart</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2015/09/15/pelican-and-github-pages-a-quickstart.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-15T17:53:08+01:00</published><updated>2015-09-15T17:53:08+01:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2015-09-15:/2015/09/15/pelican-and-github-pages-a-quickstart.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;A quick post on how to get started with Pelican using Github pages.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; quick howto !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="set-up-a-github-io-page"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Set up a github.io page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create your github user page, head over to github and create two new repositories - username.github.io-src and username.github.io - &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;as explained here&lt;/a&gt;. The src repository will hold the sources of your blog and the username.github.io repository will contain the output html files that pelican generates. Since we're going to add the output directory as a submodule, &lt;strong&gt;initialise it with a readme&lt;/strong&gt; - I can't seem to add a bare git repository as a submodule in a simple way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="install-pelican"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Install Pelican&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Fedora, this is a very very simple command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code bash literal-block"&gt;
sudo dnf install python-pelican
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren't on a Fedora system, you'll have to install these packages another way, like with &lt;cite&gt;pip&lt;/cite&gt;. I'd suggest using a virtualenv, but it's up to you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code bash literal-block"&gt;
virtualenv blog_virt
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; blog_virt
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;source&lt;/span&gt; bin/activate

pip install pelican ghp-import &lt;span class="c1"&gt;#then change to your git repository and continue&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="set-up-the-blog-with-pelican"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Set up the blog with pelican&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pelican provides an excellent quickstart command. Double check that you're working in the source git repository using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code bash literal-block"&gt;
git remote -v
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, clone the output repository as a git submodule:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code bash literal-block"&gt;
git submodule add git&amp;#64;github.com:sanjayankur31/sanjayankur31.github.io.git output &lt;span class="c1"&gt;#replace the URL with the correct one.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code bash literal-block"&gt;
pelican-quickstart
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It'll ask you various questions, just answer them. If you're using the latest version of Pelican, it'll ask you if you want to use github pages and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open the &lt;cite&gt;publishconf.py&lt;/cite&gt; file and set the &lt;cite&gt;DELETE_OUTPUT_DIRECTORY&lt;/cite&gt; variable to False. Otherwise, each time you publish, it deletes your submodule - we don't want that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tweaks"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tweaks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are various &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican/wiki/Tips-n-Tricks"&gt;tweaks and tips&lt;/a&gt; mentioned here that you should look at. One of the more handy ones is the addition of a newpost command in the Makefile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="first-post"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;First post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/3.6.3/content.html"&gt;Write a quick post&lt;/a&gt;!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="build-commit-push-and-you-re-done"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Build, commit, push, and you're done!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once done, you build your blog and check if everything is OK:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code bash literal-block"&gt;
make html&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; make serve &lt;span class="c1"&gt;#creates a demo site and serves it on localhost:8000&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This runs a local webserver on port 8000 - &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://localhost:8000"&gt;direct your browser there&lt;/a&gt; to see the results of your work!
If everything is OK, generate the website, add your files, commit them, and push to your repositories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="code bash literal-block"&gt;
make publish &lt;span class="c1"&gt;#creates the complete site
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Commit to the output submodule first
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; output
git add .
git commit -m &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;First post.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
git push -u origin master

&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# The commit the source repository
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; ..
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;'*.pyc'&lt;/span&gt; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; .gitignore &lt;span class="c1"&gt;#don't need pyc files
&lt;/span&gt;git add .
git commit -m &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;First commit.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
git push -u origin master
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Sources committed&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all! Head over the username.github.io and see the new site you've just created!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="caveats-and-customisations"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Caveats and customisations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything can be pretty much customised in Pelican. To start with, there are &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pelicanthemes.com"&gt;a set of themes that you can choose from&lt;/a&gt;. On top of that, you even have &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-plugins"&gt;a set of plug-ins&lt;/a&gt; that help you add various functionalities to your site. Of course, you can write your own or customise existing plugins and themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a tool called ghp-pages that the pelican documentation refers to, but as of Pelican 3.6.3 which Fedora 22 features, the tool doesn't work as described in the documentation. It's why I used the submodule method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Fedora"></category><category term="Pelican"></category><category term="Programming"></category><category term="Social"></category></entry><entry><title>So long, and thanks for all the fish.</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2015/05/25/so-long-and-thanks-for-all-the-fish.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-25T14:07:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-05-25T14:07:00+01:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2015-05-25:/2015/05/25/so-long-and-thanks-for-all-the-fish.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p class="first last"&gt;A little about the hitchhikers guide to the galaxy on Towel Day.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-version="4" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"&gt;&lt;div style="padding:8px;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"&gt; &lt;div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=" margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;"&gt; &lt;a href="https://instagram.com/p/3Gajf3hy5h/" style=" color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;" target="_top"&gt;&amp;#34;So long, and thanks for all the fish.&amp;#34; #towelday http://towelday.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"&gt;A photo posted by Ankur Sinha (@sanjay.ankur) on &lt;time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2015-05-25T09:41:11+00:00"&gt;May 25, 2015 at 2:41am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you didn't already know, today is &amp;quot;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://towelday.org"&gt;Towel Day&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;. If that doesn't give you ideas, you probably haven't read &amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;The hitchhikers guide to the galaxy&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;quot; yet. Well, then, before you read this post any further, you'd better get yourself a copy! &lt;em&gt;No, I'm not pulling one over you&lt;/em&gt;! Firstly, it's a book you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; should read, and secondly, probably less importantly, this post contains spoilers. In case you intend to be stubborn and read on, I'll mark paragraphs with spoilers and you can try and skip them. It'll probably make the post quite incoherent, but then, that's what you get for not listening to me, isn't it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've read quite a few books. I tend to stick to detective fiction - whodunits, locked room mysteries; science fiction - Asimov and friends; and, of course, a bit of philosophy. All of these genres appeal to me for many reasons, and one out of the plethora is that they give me things to think about - food for thought. It's rather obvious when it comes to detective fiction - understanding how Poirot or Dr. Fell or Holmes OR Bryant and May get to their conclusions is fascinating - I always end up trying to workout the chain of events myself. My affection towards science fiction comes from a rather wistful dream of witnessing true AI. Even though many have thought about it, and quite a few share my dream, the current state of research doesn't give us much hope. It is, after all, an incredibly difficult task to accomplish. We may get a collection of systems to recognise cats, but we're not very close to true AI - a conscious AI. Of course, there are many issues to consider here - especially ethical ones. On the last genre, a lot of people I meet seem to think that philosophy is for fools - that it's just a bunch of people sitting around and thinking of things that don't apply to life. Well, it isn't true. If you read and understand different philosophies, you'll notice a change in yourself - it changes the way you think, and it changes the way you act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, back to Towel Day! Towel Day is an annual celebration on the 25th of May (today!). It is a tribute to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.douglasadams.com/"&gt;Douglas Adams&lt;/a&gt; - who wrote &amp;quot;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hitchhiker%27s_Guide_to_the_Galaxy"&gt;The hitchhikers guide to the galaxy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; in 1979. The book is remarkable - unlike any that you'll read. It is obviously a humorous book (all knowing Wikipedia classifies it as &amp;quot;comedy science fiction&amp;quot;) - and it tells the story of the strangest chain of (unearthly) events that one could experience. On this day, people remember Douglas Adams by carrying a towel with them - wherever they go. Why a towel? Well, the book explains it so (&lt;strong&gt;spoiler alert!&lt;/strong&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just about the most massively useful thing any interstellar Hitchhiker can carry. Partly it has great practical value. You can wrap it around you for warmth as you bound across the cold moons of Jaglan Beta; you can lie on it on the brilliant marble-sanded beaches of Santraginus V, inhaling the heady sea vapours; you can sleep under it beneath the stars which shine so redly on the desert world of Kakrafoon; use it to sail a miniraft down the slow heavy River Moth; wet it for use in hand-to-hand combat; wrap it round your head to ward off noxious fumes or avoid the gaze of the Ravenous Bugblatter Beast of Traal (a mind-bogglingly stupid animal, it assumes that if you can't see it, it can't see you -- daft as a brush, but very very ravenous); you can wave your towel in emergencies as a distress signal, and of course you can dry yourself off with it if it still seems to be clean enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, a towel has immense psychological value. For some reason, if a strag (strag: nonhitchhiker) discovers that a hitchhiker has his towel with him, he will automatically assume that he is also in possession of a toothbrush, washcloth, soap, tin of biscuits, flask, compass, map, ball of string, gnat spray, wet-weather gear, space suit etc., etc. Furthermore, the strag will then happily lend the hitchhiker any of these or a dozen other items that the hitchhiker might accidentally have &amp;quot;lost.&amp;quot; What the strag will think is that any man who can hitch the length and breadth of the Galaxy, rough it, slum it, struggle against terrible odds, win through and still knows where his towel is, is clearly a man to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence a phrase which has passed into hitch hiking slang, as in &amp;quot;Hey, you sass that hoopy Ford Prefect? There's a frood who really knows where his towel is.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Douglas Adams - The hitchhikers guide to the galaxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the beauty of a book, any book, is that every person that reads it has his own, very personal, understanding of the text. Two people may read the exact same part of a book, but the way they'll imagine it, the way they paint their word pictures, is different. People also take away different things from books. Some take away facts, some take away lessons, and so on, and some just enjoy the book and don't take away anything at all. The hitchhikers guide to the galaxy gave me ample food for thought - I took away quite a bit. I won't discuss it all because this isn't a book report, but I will give one example that stays with me even today. Hopefully, by the end of this post, you'll want to read the book yourself - whether it's to enjoy it, or because you're looking for fresh things to think about - isn't that why we're human - because we think - and because we think, we need more material to think about - curiosity - is completely up to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoiler alert&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a part in the books where &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; turn up at the &amp;quot;Restaurant at the End of the Universe&amp;quot;. The end of the universe, it is, but not in space, &lt;em&gt;it is the end of the universe in time&lt;/em&gt;. At this restaurant, they have a rather interesting experience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He sat down.
The waiter approached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Would you like to see the menu?' he said, 'or would you like meet the Dish of the Day?'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Huh?' said Ford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Huh?' said Arthur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Huh?' said Trillian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'That's cool,' said Zaphod, 'we'll meet the meat.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt; snip &amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large dairy animal approached Zaphod Beeblebrox's table,
a large fat meaty quadruped of the bovine type with
large watery eyes, small horns and what might almost have
been an ingratiating smile on its lips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Good evening', it lowed and sat back heavily on its haunches,
'I am the main Dish of the Day. May I interest you in the parts
of my body?'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It harrumphed and gurgled a bit, wriggled its hind quarters in
to a more comfortable position and gazed peacefully at them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its gaze was met by looks of startled bewilderment from
Arthur and Trillian, a resigned shrug from Ford Prefect and
naked hunger from Zaphod Beeblebrox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Something off the shoulder perhaps?' suggested the animal,
'Braised in a white wine sauce?'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Er, your shoulder?' said Arthur in a horrified whisper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'But naturally my shoulder, sir,' mooed the animal contentedly,
'nobody else's is mine to offer.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zaphod leapt to his feet and started prodding and feeling
the animal's shoulder appreciatively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Or the rump is very good,' murmured the animal. 'I've been
exercising it and eating plenty of grain, so there's a lot
of good meat there.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It gave a mellow grunt, gurgled again and started to chew
the cud. It swallowed the cud again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Or a casserole of me perhaps?' it added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'You mean this animal actually wants us to eat it?' whispered
Trillian to Ford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Me?' said Ford, with a glazed look in his eyes, 'I don't mean
anything.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'That's absolutely horrible,' exclaimed Arthur, 'the most revolting
thing I've ever heard.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'What's the problem Earthman?' said Zaphod, now transferring his
attention to the animal's enormous rump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'I just don't want to eat an animal that's standing there
inviting me to,' said Arthur, 'It's heartless.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Better than eating an animal that doesn't want to be
eaten,' said Zaphod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'That's not the point,' Arthur protested. Then he thought about it
for a moment. 'Alright,' he said, 'maybe it is the point. I don't
care, I'm not going to think about it now. I'll just ... er ... I
think I'll just have a green salad,' he muttered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'May I urge you to consider my liver?' asked the animal,
'it must be very rich and tender by now, I've been force-feeding
myself for months.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'A green salad,' said Arthur emphatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'A green salad?' said the animal, rolling his eyes disapprovingly
at Arthur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Are you going to tell me,' said Arthur, 'that I shouldn't have
green salad?'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Well,' said the animal, 'I know many vegetables that are
very clear on that point. Which is why it was eventually
decided to cut through the while tangled problem and breed
an animal that actually wanted to be eaten and was capable of
saying so clearly and distinctly. And here I am.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It managed a very slight bow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Glass of water please,' said Arthur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Look,' said Zaphod, 'we want to eat, we don't want to make
a meal of the issues. Four rare stakes please, and hurry.
We haven't eaten in five hundred and seventy-six thousand
million years.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The animal staggered to its feet. It gave a mellow gurgle.
'A very wise choice, sir, if I may say so. Very good,' it
said, 'I'll just nip off and shoot myself.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He turned and gave a friendly wink to Arthur.
'Don't worry, sir,' he said, 'I'll be very humane.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It waddled unhurriedly off to the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&amp;mdash;Douglas Adams - The hitchhikers guide to the galaxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a hilarious, somewhat disturbing, episode, but it makes you think - well, it makes me think - &lt;em&gt;hopefully it makes you think&lt;/em&gt;. What would you do? Would you eat an animal that goal of who's life is to become your meal? Why would you? &lt;strong&gt;Why would you not&lt;/strong&gt;? If you do eat meat, you're probably eating an animal that didn't want to be eaten - is that better or worse than this scenario? I do have an answer, but I'm going to keep it to myself. You don't need to think about this at all if you don't want to - I'm not holding a gun to your head here - I have already met someone that admonished me for asking her this question - and I don't feel like being reprimanded again for thinking freely any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this day, this is my minuscule tribute to Douglas Adams, who, even though I haven't the pleasure of having met in person, I regard a great, free, mind - you are on the Internet and the internet does not forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;So long, and thanks for all the fish.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Books"></category><category term="Social"></category></entry><entry><title>Happy holidays!</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2011/12/24/happy-holidays.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-12-24T19:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-12-24T19:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2011-12-24:/2011/12/24/happy-holidays.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;500&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Merry Christmas!
by Kelvin Servigon, on Flickr&amp;quot;]&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/kelvinservigon/5287155715/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Merry Christmas!" src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5202/5287155715_d45cc27e2a.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subject says it all! Happy holiday season all! Enjoy Christmas and
the new year!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;aligncenter&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;500&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;Merry Christmas!
by Kelvin Servigon, on Flickr&amp;quot;]&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/kelvinservigon/5287155715/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Merry Christmas!" src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5202/5287155715_d45cc27e2a.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subject says it all! Happy holiday season all! Enjoy Christmas and
the new year!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Social"></category></entry><entry><title>From QC</title><link href="http://ankursinha.in/2010/07/31/from-qc.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-07-31T09:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2010-07-31T09:11:00+01:00</updated><author><name>ankur</name></author><id>tag:ankursinha.in,2010-07-31:/2010/07/31/from-qc.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thought I'd read up some &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://questionablecontent.net"&gt;QC&lt;/a&gt; (I don't feel like working at the
moment).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://questionablecontent.net/view.php?comic=27"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; comic strip he says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you send me angry, tear-stained e(mo)mails, let me just say
that you are perfectly entitled to enjoy listening to any of the
bands that Marten and Faye …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thought I'd read up some &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://questionablecontent.net"&gt;QC&lt;/a&gt; (I don't feel like working at the
moment).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://questionablecontent.net/view.php?comic=27"&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; comic strip he says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you send me angry, tear-stained e(mo)mails, let me just say
that you are perfectly entitled to enjoy listening to any of the
bands that Marten and Faye are wishing to assault in today's strip.
I would never begrudge someone their taste in music. It's such a
subjective thing that there really is no &amp;quot;right&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;wrong&amp;quot; when it
comes to one's listening habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flipside of that coin, though, is that I AM perfectly entitled
to make fun of emo bands for being Goddamned crybabies who take
themselves too seriously. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;+1 to that!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Social"></category></entry></feed>